Okay so welcome back to deep learning lesson 2
Last week we
Got to the point where we had successfully trained a pretty accurate
image classifier and
So just to remind you about how we did that
Can you guys see okay, I think the actually we can turn... can you guys all see the screen okay?
We can to adjust these ones can we?
Don't pitch us all into darkness, but if that works then
Is that okay, that's better isn't it yeah?
Can I do the other two and maybe that one as well oh
But that one oh, that's great, sorry, I don't know your renders. Oh, okay great. That's better isn't it me?
So just to remind you the way that we built this image classifier was we used a small amount of code
Basically three lines of code
And these three lines of code pointed at a particular path
Which already had some data in it and so the key thing for this to know how to train this model
was that this path which was data dogs cats and had to have a particular structure, which is that it had a
train folder and a valid folder and
In each of those trained and valid folders there was a cats folder in the dogs folder
And if the cats on the docs folders was a bunch of images of cats and dogs, but this is like a pretty standard
It's one of two
Main structures that are used to say here is
The data that I want you to train an image model from so I know some of you during the week
Went away and tried different data sets where you had
folders with different sets of images and in credit your own image classifiers
And generally that seems to be working pretty well from what I can see on the forums so to make it clear
at this point this is
Everything you need
to get started so if you
Create your own folders with different sets of images. You know a few hundred
or a few thousand at each folder
And run the same three lines of code that will give you an image classifier
And you'll be able to see this third column tells you how accurate is?
So
We looked at
Some kind of simple visualizations to see like
What was it uncertain about? What was it wrong about and so forth and that's always a really good idea
and
Then we learned about the one key number you have to pick so this is this number here
Is the one key number is 0.01 and this is called the learning rate, and so I wanted to go over this again
And we'll learn about the theory behind what this is?
During the rest of the course in quite a lot of detail and for now I just wanted to talk about the practice
Yes, Yannet.
They cannot see you in the video. They can now. I just turned it around
You tell us about the other three numbers being bad, we did
These three here
We're going to talk about the other other ones shortly so the main one we're going to look at for now is is the last
Column which is the accuracy the?
First column as you can see is the epoch number so this tells us how many times has it been through the entire dataset
Trying to learn a better classifier and in the next two columns is what's called the loss which we'll be learning about
Either later today or next week the first point is the loss on the training set
These are the images that we're looking at in order to try to make a better classifier
And the second is the loss of the validation set these are the images that we're not looking at and we're training
But we're just sitting on the side to see how accurate we are so we'll learn about littering loss in accuracy
later
Okay, so
So we've got the epoch number the training loss is the second column the
Validation loss is the third column and the accuracy is the fourth column?
Okay, so the basic idea of the loading rate
So the basic idea of the learning rate is it's the thing that's going to decide how quickly do we zoom do we kind of
Hone in on the solution, and so I find that a good way to think about this is to think about like well
What if we were trying to?
fit to a function that
Looks something like this right. We're trying to say okay. Where's where abouts is the minimum point?
This is basically what we do when we do deep learning is we try to find the minimum point of a function
Now our function happens to have
Millions, or hundreds of millions of parameters, but it works the same basic way, and so when we look at it
you know we can immediately see that the
Lowest point is here
But how would you do that if you are a computer algorithm and what we do is we we start out at some point
At random so you pick say here, and we have a look and we say okay
What's the what's the loss or the error at this point?
And we say what's the gradient in other words which way is up and which way is down and?
It tells us that down is going to be in that direction and it also tells us how fast is it going down?
Which is at this point is going down pretty quickly?
And so then we take a step in
The direction that's down and the distance we travel is going to be
Proportional to the gradient sort of unfortunately how steep it is the idea is if it's deeper, then we're probably further away
That's the general idea right and so specifically what we do is we take the gradient
Which is how steep is it at this point, and we multiply it by some number and that number is called the learning rate?
Okay, so if we pick a number that is
very small
Then we're guaranteed that we're going to go a little bit closer and a little bit closer and a little bit closer each time
Right, but it's going to take us a very long time to eventually get to the bottom if we dig a number
That's very big. We could actually step too far could go in the right direction, but we could step all the way over to here
Right as result of which we end up further away than we started and we could
Oscillate and get worse and worse so if you start training a neural net and you find that your accuracy or your loss is like
Spitting off into infinity almost certainly your learning rates too high
so in a sense learning rate too low is
Is a better problem to have because you're going to have to wait a long time, but wouldn't it be nice
if there was a way to figure out like
What's the best learning rate something where you could kind of go quickly go like Bom Bom Bom right and so?
That's why we use this thing called a learning rate finder
And what the learning rate finder does is it tries each each time it looks at another remember the?
Mini-batch how many batches a few images that we look at each time so that we're using the parallel processing power of the GPU
Effectively we look generally at around
64 128 images at a time for each mini batch, which is labeled here as an iteration
We gradually increase the learning rate
multiplicatively increase the learning rate
We started really really tiny learning rates to make sure that we don't start at something too high and we gradually
Increase it and so the idea is that?
Eventually the learning rate will be so big that the loss will start getting worse and so what we're going to do
Then is we're a look at the plot of
Learning rate against loss right so when the learning rates tiny
It increases slowly, then it's that's where increase a bit faster
And then eventually it starts not increasing as quickly and in fact it starts getting worse
Right so clearly here and make sure you're you want to be familiar with this
Scientific notation okay so ten to the negative one is
0.1. 10 to 50 or is 1 10 to the negative 2 is 0.001 and when we write this in
Python we'll generally write it like this rather than writing 10 to the negative 1 or 10 to the negative 2
we'll just write 1 a
Neg 1 or 1 e neg - okay. I mean the same thing you're going to see that all the time
And remember that equals 0.1. Oh point O one
Okay, so
Don't be confused by this text that it prints out here this this loss
Here is the the final loss at the very at the end of it's not of any interest right so ignore this this is only
interesting when we're doing regular trading
That's not interesting for the learning rate finder the thing that's interesting for the learning rate finder. Is this loan shed plot and
Specifically we're not looking for the point where it's the lowest back to the point where it's the lowest it's actually not getting better anymore
So that's to higher learning rate
So I generally look to see like where is it the lowest and then I go back like one for magnitude so?
one enoch two
Would be a pretty good choice
Yeah, okay, so that's why you saw when we ran our
Fit here we picked 0.01 right which is one a neg two
So important point to make here is like this this is the one key number that we've learnt
to adjust
and
if
You just adjust this number at nothing else most of the time you're going to be able to get pretty good results
And this is like a very different message to what you would hear or see in any textbook or any video or any course
because
Up until now
there's been like dozens and dozens of these they're called hyper parameters dozens and dozens of hyper parameters to set and
They've been thought of as highly sensitive and difficult to set so inside the first AI library
We kind of do all that stuff for you
as much as we can and
During the course we're going to learn that there are some more we can quake to get slightly better results
But it's kind of like
It's kind of in a funny situation
Here because for those of you that haven't done anything learning before is kind of like oh this is
That's all there is to it. This is very easy, and then when you talk to people outside this class
They'll be like deep learning so difficult as someone to say it's a real art form and so that's why there's this
as is difference right and so that the truth is that the learning rate really is the key thing to set and
This ability to use this to figure out how to set it well though the paper is now
probably 18 months old
Almost nobody knows about this paper. It was from a guy
Who's not from a famous research labs so most people kind of ignored it and in fact even this particular technique was one
subpart of a paper that was about something else
So again this idea of like this is how you can set the learning rate?
Really nobody outside this classroom just about knows about it obviously the guy who wrote it Leslie Smith knows about it. Yeah
So it's a good thing to tell your colleagues about is like here is actually a great way to set the learning rate and
There's even been papers caught like one of the famous papers is called no more pesky learning rates
Which actually is a less effective technique than this one?
But this idea that like setting learning rates is
Is very difficult and thirdly is has been true for most of the kind of deep learning history
So here's the trick right go look at this plot
Find kind of the lowest to go back about a multiple of ten and try that all right
And if that doesn't quite work you can always try you know going back another multiple ten, but this is always worked for me
so far
Once
Why does this learning rate? This method work versus something else like momentum base?
Or what's like the advantages a disadvantage with just learning rate rate like technique. We're just feels
That's a great question so
We're going to learn during this course about a number of ways of improving
gradient percent like you mentioned momentum and
atom and so forth
This is orthogonal in fact so one of the things the faster a library tries to do is figure out the right
Gradient descent version and in fact behind the scenes
This is actually using something called Adam and so this technique is telling us. This is the best learning rate to use
given
What I thought other tweaks you're using in this case the atom optimizer
So it's not that there's some compromise between this and some other approaches who sits on top of those approaches
And you still have to set the learning rate when you use with other approaches
So we're trying to find the best
Kind of optimizer to use for a problem that you still have to set the learning rate
And this is how we can do it and in fact this idea of using this technique on top of
more advanced optimizers like Adam might haven't even seen
Mentioned in a paper before so I think this is like a I mean
It's not a huge breakthrough. It seems obvious but nobody else seems to
Tried it so as you can see it was well
When we use
optimizers like Adam ditched Harvick adaptive learning rate so and he said this learning rate is Italy initial learning rate because it changes during the
people
So
We're going to be learning about things like Adam the details about it later in the class
But the basic answer is no even with even the Adam that there actually is a learning rate
It's just being
It's being basically divided by the the gradient
The average previous gradient and also the recent summer Squared's of gradients
So there's still like a number called the learning rate there. There. Isn't a even these so called dynamic learning rate
methods still have
unlearning rate
Okay, so
The most important
Thing that you can do to make your model better and is to give it more data
So the challenge that happens is that these models have hundreds of millions of parameters
and if you train them for a while they start to
Do what's called overfitting and so overfitting means that they're going to start to see like the specific details of the images you're giving them?
rather than the more general
Learning that can transfer across to the validation set
So the best thing we can do to avoid overfitting is to find more data
Now obviously one way to do that would just be to collect more data from where you're getting it from or label more data
But a really easy way that we should always do is to use something called data augmentation
So they don't open tuition is one of these things that's key in many courses
It's not even mentioned at all or if it is it's kind of like an advanced topic right at the end
But actually it's like the most important thing that you can do to make a better model, okay?
And so it's built into the faster you library to make it very easy to do and so we're going to look at the details
Of the code shortly, but the basic idea is that?
as in our initial code
We had a line that said image classified data from parts
And we passed in the path to our data and for transforms. We passed in basically
The sizing the architecture. We'll look at this in more detail shortly
We just add one more parameter, which is what kind of data augmentation do you want to do?
and so
To understand data augmentation, it's may. Be easiest to look at some pictures of data augmentation so what I've done here again
We'll look at the code in more detail later, but the basic idea is oh I've run
I've built a
Data class like multiple times. I'm going to do it six times and each time. I'm going to plot the same catch and
You can see that what happens is that?
This cap here is further over to the left this one here is further over to the right and this one here is fit
horizontally and so forth so data augmentation
Different types of image you're going to want different types of data augmentation right so for example if you were trying to recognize
Letters and digits you wouldn't want to flip horizontally because like it's actually has a different meaning
Whereas on the other hand if you're looking at?
Photos of cats and dogs you probably don't want to fit vertically because cats aren't generally upside down all right
Where else if you're looking at there's a current Cargill competition which is?
recognizing
Icebergs in satellite images you probably do want to fit them upside down
Because it's really matter which area around the iceberg or the satellite was right so
One of the examples of the transform sets we have is
Transforms sidon so in other words if you have photos that are like generally taken from the side
Which generally means you want to be able to flip them horizontally, but not vertically
This is going to give you all the transforms you need for that so it'll flip them sideways
Rotate them by small amounts but not too much and slightly bury their contrast and brightness
And slightly zoom in and out a little bit and move them around a little so each time it's a slightly different fight billionaires
We're getting a couple of questions from people about
You explaining in the reason why you don't think the minimum of the loss curve
Yeah, but it's like the higher rate so yeah, and also could you?
people understand if
This works for every CNN for CNN every minute. There's a running right fine done. Yeah, exactly, yeah
Okay great, um could you put your hand up if there's a spare seat next to you?
So there was a question about the learning rate finder about why do we use the learning rate?
That's less than the lowest point and so the reason why is to understand what's going on with this learning rate finder
So let's go back to our picture here
Like how do we figure out what learning rate to use right and so what we're going to do is we're going to take
Steps and each time we're going to double
The learning rate so kind of double the amount by which we multiply the grander gradient so in other words would go
tiny step slightly bigger slightly bigger slightly bigger
slightly bigger
Slightly bigger
okay, and
so the question is of the purpose of this is not to find the minimum the
Purpose of this is to figure out what learning rate is allowing us to decrease quickly, right?
So the point at which the loss was lowest here is actually there, right?
But that learning rate actually looks like it's probably too high it's going to just jump like
Probably backwards and forwards, okay?
So instead what we do is we go back to the point where the learning rates quickly are giving us a quick increase
in the loss
So here is so here is the actual learning rate increasing every single time. We look at a new mini batch
so mini-batch reiteration versus learning right and
Then here is learning rate versus loss, so here's that point at the bottom. Where is now already too high?
Okay, and so here's the point where we go back a little bit, and it's increasing nice and quickly
We're going to learn about something called
stochastic gradient descent with restarts
Shortly where we're going to see like in a sense you might want to go back to 1 enoch 3 where it's actually even steeper
Still and maybe we would actually find this book
actually
Learn even quicker you could try it, but we're going to see later
Why actually using a higher number is going to give us better generalization so?
For now let's put that aside
Do you mean higher learning rate when you say I?
Know I mean higher letting retina say higher. Yeah, yeah
I
Mean I am learning rate so as we increase the iterations from the learning rate finder the learning rate is going up
This is iterations versus learning ready. Okay, so as we
Do that as the learning rate increases and we plot it here?
the loss Goes Down and here we get to the point where the learning rate is too high and
At that point the most is now getting worse
Because I asked the question because you were just indicating that you know even though the minimum was at 10 to the minus 1
You were gonna you suggest that we should choose 10 to the minus 2, but now you're saying
I mean we should go back the other way higher
So I didn't mean to say that I'm sorry if I said something backwards. I want to go back down to the
Lower learning rate, so possibly. I said a higher when I meant higher
Into this lower OS. Do you know I'm learning right? Okay? Thanks. Yep
Last class is said that the local all the local minima are the same and
This graph also shows the same is that is this something that was observed, or is the logic theory behind it
That's not what this graph is showing
This graph is simply showing that there's a point where if we increase the learning rate more
Then it stops getting better than actually starts getting worse the idea that
all local minima are the same is a
totally separate issue
and
It's actually something else. We'll see a picture of shortly, so let's come back to that
Jeremy do we have to find the base learning rate every time we are going to
run a poke
third time we're
Running on a poke and a pop so how many times should I run this like let me write find
my training
That's a great question unit um
I
Certainly run it once when I start
Later on in this class we're going to learn about unfreezing layers
and
After I unfreeze layers, I sometimes run it again if I do something to like change the thing I'm training or change the way
I'm training it you may want to run it again
basically
Or you know if you particularly if you've changed something about how you train like
Unfreezing layers, which we're gonna soon learn about and you're finding the other training is
Unstable or too slow well again you can run it again. There's never any harm
In running it it doesn't take very long
That's great question
Okay, so back to data augmentation so if we add to a when we run this little transforms from model
function we pass in orientation transforms, we can pass in the main to a
Transform side on or transforms top down later on we'll learn about creating your own custom transform lists as well
but for now because we're taking pictures from the side cats and dogs will say transform side on and
Now each time we look at an image. It's going to be zoomed in or out a little bit moved around a little bit
rotated a little bit
Possibly flipped okay, and so what this does is it's not exactly creating new data, but as far as the
Convolutional neural net is concerned. It's a different way of looking at this thing and it actually therefore allows it to learn
how to recognize cats or dogs
From somewhat different angles right so when we do data orientation. We're basically trying to say based on our domain knowledge
Here here are different ways that we can mess with this image that we know still make it the same image
You know and that we could expect that you might actually see that kind of image in the real world
So what we can do now is when we call this from parts function
Which we'll learn more about shortly we can now pass in this set of transforms, which actually have these augmentations in
now
So that's going to we're going to start from scratch here. We do a fit and
Initially
the
Augmentations actually don't do anything and the reason initially they don't do anything is because we've got here something that says
Precompute equals true. We're going to come back to these lots of times
But basically what this is doing is do you remember this picture we saw where we learn each different layer
Has these activations that basically look for it or anything from the middle of flowers to?
eyeballs of
Birds or whatever right and so literally what happens is that?
The the later layers of this convolutional neural network have these things called activations and activation literally
It's a number an activation is a number that says this feature like
Eyeball of bird is in this location with this level of confidence with its probability
right and so we're going to see a lot of this later, but
What we can do is we can say all right well in this
We've got a pre trained network remember and a pre trained network is one where it's already learned to recognize
Certain things in this case it's learnt to recognize the one and a half million images in the imagenet dataset
And so what we could do is we could take the the second last layer, so the one which is like
Got all of the information necessary to figure out
What kind of thing a thing is and we can save those activations so basically saving things saying you know?
There's this level of eyeball nurse here in this level of dogs facing us here or in this level of
Fluffy ear there and so forth and so we save for every image these
Activations and that we call them the pre computed activations
And so the idea is now that when we want to create a new classifier
Which can basically take advantage of these pre computed applications?
We can just very quickly train when all the details there shortly we can very quickly train a simple linear model
Based on those and so that's what happens when we say pre-compute equals true
And that's why you may have noticed this week the first time that you run a model a new model
It takes a minute or two
Where else you saw when I ran it it took like five or ten seconds
Took you a minute or two and that's because it had to pre-compute
These activations and just has to do that once if you're using like your own computer or AWS
It just has to do it once ever
If you're using Kressel it actually has to do it once
Every single time you rerun press all because press or uses are
Just for these pre computed activations
It uses a special that all had a scratch space that disappears each time you restart your press or instance
So other than the special case of cresol generally speak. He does have to run at once ever
For a data set okay
So the issue with that is that since we pre computed for each image
You know how much does it have an EI here and how much does it have a?
Lizard's eyeball there and so forth that means that data augmentations don't work right in other words even though
We're trying to show at a different version of the cat each time. We've pre computed the activations for a particular version of that cat
So in order to use data augmentation. We just have to go and learn pre compute equals false
Okay, and then we can run a few more
APIs right
And so you can see here that as we run more a Potts
The accuracy isn't particularly getting better. That's the bad news the good news is that?
You can see that the train loss
Practices like the way of measuring the error of this model although
That's getting better the errors going down the validation error isn't
Going down and but we're not overfitting and overfitting would mean that the training
Loss is much lower than the validation loss, and we're going to talk about that a lot during this course
But the general idea
Here is if you're doing much better job on
The training set then you are on the validation set that means your models not generalize
So we're not at that point which is good, but we're not really improving
So we're going to have to figure out how to deal with that
Before we do I want to show you one other cool trick. I've added here
Cycle length equals one
And this is another really interesting idea
Here's the basic idea
cycle length equals one enables a
recent fairly recent discovery and deep learning called stochastic gradient descent with restarts and the basic idea is this as
you
As you get closer and closer as you get closer and closer
to the right spot, right
Now getting closer and closer I may want to start to decrease my learning rate right because as I get closer
I'm kind of like oh, I'm pretty close down, so let's let's slow down my steps to try to get executive the right spot
Right and so as we do more iterations
Our learning rate
Perhaps should actually go
Down right because as we go along we're getting closer and closer to where we want to be and we want to like get exactly
to the right spot
Okay, so the idea of decreasing the learning rate as you train is called learning rate
annealing and
It's it's very very common very very popular
Everybody uses it basically all the time
the most common kind of learning rate annealing is
Really horrendously hacky. It's basically that researchers like pick a learning rate that seems to work for a while
And then when it stops learning well they drop it down by about 10 times
And then they keep learning a bit more until it doesn't seem to be improving and they drop it down by another ten times
That's what most academic research papers and most people in industry do so this would be like stepwise annealing very manual
very annoying a
Better approach is simply to pick some kind of functional form like a line
It turns out that a really good functional form is one half of the cosine curve
Right and the reason why is that for a while when you're not very close
You kind of have a really high learning rate, and that is you do get close
You kind of quickly drop down and do a few iterations with a really low learning rate, and so this is called cosine annealing
So to those of you who haven't done trigonometry for a while cosine basically looks something like this right, so we've picked
one little half piece
Okay, so we're going to use cosine annealing
But here's the thing
When you're in a very?
High dimensional space right near we're only able to show three dimensions right but in reality. We've got hundreds of millions of dimensions
We've got lots of
different
Fairly flat points there. No not the actual local minima, but they're fairly flat points all of which are pretty good, right?
But they might differ in a really interesting way, which is that some of those flat points?
Let me show you
Let's imagine we've got a surface that looks something like this
Right now imagine that where you kind of random guest started here and
Our initial therefore kind of learning rate annealing schedule got us down to here
now
Indeed that's a pretty nice low error right, but it probably doesn't generalize very well
Which is to say if we use a different data set where things are just kind of slightly different in one of these directions
Suddenly is a terrible solution right where else over here
is basically
equally good in terms of loss, right
But it rather suggests that if you move if you have slightly different data sets that are slightly moved in different directions
It's still going to be good right so in other words. We would expect this solution. Here is probably going to generalize better
than this by key one
So here's what we do is. We've got like a bunch of different low bits right then our standard
Loading rate annealing approach will start of go down here or downhill downhill downhill downhill to one spot
Right, but what we could do instead is use a learning rate schedule
That looks like this
Which is to say we do a cosign annealing and then suddenly jump up again into a cosign annealing and then jump up again?
And so each time we jump up it means that if they're going to spiky bit
and then we subtly increase the learning rate, and it jumps now all the way over to here and
So then we kind of learning right in your learning right near death down to here
And then we jump up again to a high learning rate oh
And it stays here right so in other words each time
We jump up the learning rate that means that if it's in a nasty spiky part of the surface
It's going to hop out of the spiky part, and hopefully if we do that enough times
It'll eventually find a nice
smooth Bowl
Could you get the same effect by running multiple iterations through the different ground of my starting point so that
Eventually you explore all possible minimize
yeah, so in fact that that's a great question and
before this
approach
Which is called stochastic gradient descent with restarts was was created
That's exactly what people used to do. They used to create these things called ensembles where they would basically
Relearn a whole new model ten times in the hope that one of them's like but it ended up being better
and so
The cool thing about this decosta gradient descent with restarts is that the model once? We're in a reasonably good spot
Each time we jump up the learning rate
It doesn't restart it actually hangs out in this nice part part of the space and then keeps getting better
So interestingly it turns out that this approach where we do this
a bunch of separate cosine annealing steps we end up with a better result as
Then if we just randomly try it a few different starting points
so it's a super neat trick and it's a
fairly recent development
But and again almost nobody's heard of it
But I found like
it's now like my superpower like using this along with the learning rate finder like I
Can get better results than nearly anybody like in a casual competition
You know in the first week or two I can like jump in it's been an arrow to and back
I've got a fantastically good result and so this is why I
Didn't pick the point where it's got the steepest slope. I actually trying to pick something kind of aggressively high
It's still getting down
But maybe like getting to the point where it's nearly too high
Not because I want to make sure because that's because when we do this
stochastic gradient descent with restarts this ten to the negative two represents the a
Highest number that it uses so it goes up to ten to the negative two and then goes down
And then up to ten negative two and down so if I use to lower learning rate
It's not going to jump to a different part of the function
So I have a few questions, but the first one is how many times do you change your learning rate you want to work?
We don't change the learning rate all three
How many times - okay so in terms of this part here where it's going down?
We change the learning rate every single mini - all right, and then the number of times. We reset it is set by the
Cycle length parameter, and so 1 means reset it up to every epoch
so if I had to there it would reset it up to every to epochs and
Interestingly this this point that when we do the learning rate and kneeling that we actually change it every single batch
It turns out to be
Really critical to making this work, and it again is very different to what nearly everybody in industry in academia has done before
What do you get a chance could you explain recompute it was true because it's still
Yeah, we're going to come back to that
Multiple times in this course so the way this course has been a work is we're going to like do a really high-level
Version of each thing and then we're going to like come back to it in two or three lessons and then come back to it
at the end of the course and each time we're going to see like more of the math more of the code and get a
Deeper view okay, and we can talk about it also in the forums
During the week
Our main goal is to generalize, and we don't want to get those like narrow
Demas yeah, that's a it's a very short. Summary. This method are we keeping track off to minimize and averaging them? Ah?
That's that's another
Level of sophistication and indeed you can see there's something here called snapshot ensemble, so we're not doing it in the code right now
But yes if you wanted to make us generalize even better
You can save the weights here and here and here and then take the average ishes
But for now we're just going to pick the last one
If you want to skip ahead
If you want to skip ahead there's a parameter called cycle safe name
Which you can add as well as cycle them, and that will save a set of weights at the end of every
Learning rate cycle, and then you can ensemble them
Ok
So we've got a
Pretty decent model here ninety nine point three percent accuracy
And we've gone through of you know a few steps that is taken you know a minute or two to run
And so from time to time
I tend to save my weight so if you go learn dot save and then pass in a file name
It's going to go ahead and save that for you later on if you go learn load
You'll be straight back to where you came from okay, so it's a good idea to do that from time to time
This is a good time to mention
What happens when you do this?
When you go learn dot save when you create precomputed activations another thing we learn about soon when you create resized images
These are all creating various temporary files, okay?
And so what happens is?
If we go to
Data and
We go to
Dogs cats, this is my data folder, and you'll see there's a folder here called
TMP or - and
So this is automatically created and all of my pre computed activations end up in here. I mention this because if
If things are if you're getting weird errors that might be because you've got some Oh pre computed activations like we're only half
completed or
Are in some way incompatible with what you're doing so you can always go ahead and just delete this
TMP this temporary directory and see if that causes your error to go away. This is the
Faster I equivalent of turning it off and then on again
You'll also see there's a directory called models, and that's where all of these when you say dot save with a model
That's where that's going to go
Actually it reminds me when the stochastic gradient descent with restarts paper came out
I saw a tweet that was somebody was like Oh to make your deep learning work better turn it off and then on again
Question it
So if I want to see I want to retrain my model fuselage again do I just do everything the 10 folder if you want
If you want to train your model from scratch
There's generally no reason to delete the pre computed activations because the pre computed activations are
Without any training. That's what the pre trained model
Created with the with the weights that you downloaded off the internet
the only
Yeah, I mean the only reason you want to delete the pre computed activations is that there was some error caused by like half
Creating them and crashing or some something like that
as you change the size of your import change different architectures and so forth they all create different sets of
activations with different file names
So you don't generally you shouldn't have to worry about it
If you want to start training again from scratch all you have to do is create a new
Learn object so each time you go like conch learner dot pre-trained that creates a new
object with with new sets of weights fever train from
Okay
So before our break. We'll finish off by talking about
about fine-tuning and differential learning rates
And so so far
Everything we've done
Has not changed any of these free trained filters right so we've used a pre trained model that already knows how to find
At the early stages
edges ingredients
And then corners and curves
And then repeating patterns
and bits of text and eventually
Eyeballs, right we have not
Retrained any of those
activations any of those features
Well specifically any of those weights in the convolutional kernels all we've done is we've learnt
Some new layers that we've added on top of these things. We've learned how to mix and match these pre-trained features
Now obviously it may turn out that
Your pictures have you know different kinds of eyeballs or faces?
Or if you're using different kinds of images like satellite images
Totally different kinds of features altogether right so if you're like training to recognize
Icebergs you'll probably want to go all the way back and learn
You know all the way back to kind of different combinations of these simple gradients and edges
In our cases dogs vs. Cats
We're going to have some minor differences, but we still may find. It's helpful to slightly tune some of these
Later layers as well
So to tell the learner that we now want to start actually changing the convolutional filters themselves
We simply say unfreeze okay, so a frozen layer is a layer, which is not trained is not updated, okay?
So unfreeze unfreezes all of the layers
Now when you think about it. It's pretty obvious that
Layer one
Right which is like a diagonal edge, or a gradient?
Probably doesn't need to change by much if at all right from the 1 and a half million images on image net it probably already
Is figured out pretty well how to find like edges of gradients?
It probably already knows also like which kind of corners to look for and how to find which kinds of curves and so forth
So in other words these early layers probably need little if any
learning
Where else these later ones are much more likely to need more learning, and this is universally true regardless of whether you're looking for
Satellite images of rainforests or icebergs or whether you're looking for cats versus dogs, right?
So what we do is we create an array of learning rates
Where we say okay? These are the learning rates to use for our additional layers that we've added on top
These are the learning rates to use in the middle few layers
And these are the learning rates to use for the first few layers
So these are the ones for the layers that represent like very basic geometric
Features these are the ones that are used to for the more complex
Kind of sophisticated convolutional features, and these are the ones that are used for the features that we've added and went from stretch
right so you can create a array of learning rates and
Then when we called up fit and pass an array of learning rates. It's now going to use those different learning rates for different
parts of the model
This is not something that
We've like invented
But I'd also say it's like it's so not that common that it doesn't even have a name as far as I know so
We're going to call it
differential learning rates
If it actually has a name or indeed if somebody's actually written a paper specifically talking about it. I don't know
there's a
Great researcher called Jason your Sinskey who who did write a paper about the kind of the idea that you might want different learning rates?
and showing why
but I don't think any other libraries support it and
Yeah, I don't know of a name for it having said that though
This ability to like unfreeze and then use these differential learning rates
I found it's like the secret to taking a pretty good model and putting it into an awesome model
So just to clarify
So you have three numbers there okay three hyper parameters the first one is the photo
late model so the mall that are late layers the
So with
The it's your answer is many many right and they're kind of in groups, and we're going to learn about the architecture
This is called a ResNet for residual network
It kind of has ResNet blocks
And so what we're doing is we're grouping the blocks into three groups
And so this one is actually this first number is for the earliest layers
Yeah, they're ones closest to the pixels that represent like corners and edges and gradients, but why
Why do you well I thought those layers are frozen at first so yeah right so we just said unfreeze the streets
Also, we so yeah, I'm freezing them because you have kind of partially trained
Although lately we've trained. We've trained our added layers. Yes, now you are we training the Oh step exactly?
Obviously so it waits and the learning rate is particularly small for the early layers
That's right, because you just find a want to find food. Yeah. Yeah, we probably don't want to change them at all
But you know if it does need to then it can
Thanks, no problem
So using the differential in rates a little different from like grid search
There's no similarity to grid search so grid search is where we're trying to find the best hyper parameter
for something so for example you could kind of think of the
Learning rate finder as a really sophisticated grid search, which is like trying lots and lots of learning rates to find, which one is best
But this has nothing to do with that
This is actually for the entire training from now on it's actually going to use a different learning rate for each layer
And so I was wondering so you give a pre train model, then you have to use the same input
Dimensions right because I was thinking okay, let's say you have this big
They use like big machines to train these things and you want to take advantage of it
How would you go about you know you have like images that are like bigger than the ones that
They used or we're going to be talking about sizes later, but the short answer is that with this library and the modern
Architectures were using we can use any size we like
So did I mean do we need can we at least just a specific layer?
We can we're not doing it yet, but if you wanted to you can learn dot freeze underscore two and pass into layer number
Much to my surprise or at least initial my surprise it turns out I almost never need to do that
I almost never find it helpful, and I think it's because we're using differential learning rates
The the optimizer can kind of learn just as much as it needs to
so yeah, it's
A little data like very little data. Yeah it still
Doesn't seem to help the one place. I have found it helpful is if
I'm using like a really big memory intensive model, and I'm like running out of GPU
crazy having
The the less layers you unfreeze the less memory it takes and the less time it takes so there's that kind of practical aspect
So to me she'll say I asked the question right
Can I just like unfreezes specific layer?
No you you can only unfreeze layers from layer n onwards
You could probably delve inside the library in phase one phase one layer, but I don't know why you would
Okay, so I'm really excited to be showing you guys this stuff because it's like it's something
We've been kind of researching all year. It's figuring out how to train
state of the art models
and we've kind of found these like tiny number of tricks and so once we do that we now go learn about fit right and
You can see look at this we get right up to that
99.5%
Accuracy which is crazy
There's one other trick you might see here that as well as using stochastic gradient descent with restarts a cycle length equals one
We've done three cycles so earlier on I lied to you. I said this is this is the number of epochs
It's actually the number of cyclists right so if you said cycle length equals two it would do three
Cycles of each of two epochs or do six because so here I've said two three cycles yet somehow. It's done seven epochs
and the reason why is I've got one last trick to show you which is cycle mult equals two and
To tell you what that does I'm simply going to draw you a picture you the picture
If I go learn Dutch share top plot learning rate there it is
Now you can see what cycle mode equals to is doing okay?
It's it's doubling
The length of the cycle after each cycle and so in the paper that introduced this stochastic gradient descent with restarts
The researcher kind of said hey, this is something that seems to sometimes work pretty well
And I've certainly found that often to be the case so basically
Intuitively speaking if your cycle length is too short, right
Then it's kind of starts going down to find a good spot
And then it pops out and it goes to a try and photographs button pops out it never actually gets to find a good spot
Right so earlier on you want it to do that because it's trying to find the bit
That's like smoother, but then later on you want it to fight do more exploring and then more exploring right so that's why this
Cycle mole equals two thing often seems to be a pretty good approach right so
Suddenly we're introducing more and more hyper parameters having told you that there aren't that many?
But the reason is that like you can really get away with just
Taking a good learning rate, but then adding these extra tweaks
Really, helps get that extra level up without any effort right and so in practice I find
this kind of three cycles starting at 1 mode equals 2
Works very very often to get a pretty decent model
If it does doesn't then often I'll just do 3 cycles of length 2
With no molt. Okay. There's kind of like two things that seem to work a lot, and there's not too much fiddling
I find necessary
And as I say even even if you just if you use this line every time
I'd be surprised if you didn't get a reasonable result so a question here
Why does a smoother services correlate to more generalize networks
So it's kind of this some
This intuitive explanation, I try to just kill the whole thing. I try to give back here, which is that?
if you've got
Something spiky right and so what this
What this x-axis is showing is like how?
How good is this at recognizing dogs versus cats as you change this particular parameter right and?
So so something to be generalizable
that means that we wanted to work when we give it when we give it a slightly different data set and
So a slightly different data set may
Have a slightly different relationship between this parameter, and how caddy versus dog it is it may instead look a little bit like this
Right so in other words if we end up at this point
Right then it's not going to do a good job on this slightly different data set for else if we end up on this point
It's still going to do a good job on this data set
Okay, so that's what psychomotor equals doing okay, so we've got one last thing before we going to take a break
which is we're now going to take this model, which has 99.5 percent accuracy and we're going to try and make it better still and
what we're going to do is we're not actually going to change the model at all right, but instead we're going to look back at
The original virtual visualization, we did where we looked at some of our incorrect pictures
Now what I've done is I've printed out the whole of these incorrect pictures, but the key thing to realize is that?
Particularly in fact when we do the the validation set all of our inputs
To our model all the time have to be square right and the reason for that is
It's kind of a minor technical detail
But basically the GPU doesn't go very quickly if you have like different dimensions for different images because it needs seems to be consistent
So that every part of the GPU can do the same thing and I think this is probably fixable
But it now
That's the state of the technology we have so our validation set when we actually say for this particular thing is it's a dog
What we actually do to make it square as we just pick out
The square in the middle right so we would take off its two edges
And so we take the whole height
And then as much of the middle as we can and so you can see in this case we wouldn't actually see this dog's head
right so
I think the reason this was actually not correctly classified was because the validation set only got to see the body and the body
Doesn't look particularly doglike or cat-like. It's not at all punctual what it is, so what we're going to do
when we calculate the predictions for our validation set is we're going to use something called test time augmentation and
What this means is that every time we decide is this cat or a dog not in the training?
But after we've trained the model is we're going to actually take
Four
random data augmentations and remember the data augmentations move around
and zoom in and out and flip
okay, so we're going to take four of them at random and we're going to take the original and
Augmented sent a cropped image, and we're going to do a prediction for all of those, and then we're going to take the average
Of those predictions, so I'm going to say is this a cat is this a cat is this a cat is this a cat
But and so hopefully in one of those random ones we actually make sure that the face is there
Zoomed in by a similar amount to other dogs faces at sea
And it's rotated by the amount that it expects to see it and so forth and so do that
All we have to do is
Just call tt8 TTA stands for Test time
Augmentation this term of like what a what do we call up when we're making predictions from up from a model?
We've trained sometimes. It's called inference time sometimes
It's called test time everybody since have a different name so TTA and so when we do that
We go learn TTA check the accuracy and lo and behold we're now at ninety nine point six five percent, which is kind of crazy
Where's our green box?
But for every park we are only
Showing one type of augmentation or for particular image right so when we are training
back here
We're not doing any TTA right so TTA is not like
You could and sometimes like I've written libraries where after a cheap up I run TTA to see how well it's going
But that's not what's happening here. I trained the whole thing
with
training time organization
Which doesn't have a special name because that's what we mean when we say data
Augmentation we need training time augmentation so here every time we showed a picture
We were randomly changing it a little bit so each epoch each of these seven epochs. It was seen slightly different versions of the picture
Having done that we now have a fully trained model. We then said okay
Let's look at the validation set so TTA by default uses the validation set and said okay
What are your predictions of which ones are cats and which ones are dogs?
And it did 4
Predictions with different random orientations plus one on the organ under Augmented version average them all together
And that's what we got and that's what we can't clear the accurate
So is there a high probability of having?
Sample in TTA that was not shown in doing trained
Yeah, actually every data augmented for image is is unique because the rotation could be like point zero three four
Degrees and zoom could be 1.0. One sixty five so every time. It's slightly different
No problem was behind you
What's your
Might not use white padding or something like that
Just one of your white padding like just you know put like a white water around
Oh padding's not yes
So like there's lots of different types of a better orientation you can do and so one of the things you can do is to
Add a border around it
Basically adding a border around it in my experiments doesn't doesn't help it doesn't make it any less
Cat-like it's not the convolutional neural network doesn't seem to find it very interesting basically
Something that I do do we'll see later is I do something called reflection padding, which is where I add some borders
That are the outside just reflected. It's a way to kind of make some bigger images works well with satellite imagery in particular
But yeah in general. I don't do I have a lot of padding instead I do a bit of zooming
It's kind of follow-up to that last one but
Rather than cropping just at white space because when you crop you lose the dog's face
but if you added white space you wouldn't yeah, so that's that's where the
Kind of the reflection padding or the zooming or whatever can help so there are ways in the faster
You know library when you do custom transforms of of making that happen
I
Find that
It kind of depends on the image size you know but
Generally speaking it seems that using TTA plus data
Augmentation the best thing to do is to try to use this larger image as possible
And so if you kind of crop the thing down and put white borders on top and bottom it's now
Quite a lot smaller and so to make it as big as it was before
you now have to use more GPU and if you're going to use more that multi figure you could have zoomed in and used a
bigger image, so
In my playing around that doesn't seem to be generally as successful
There is a little interest on the topic of how do the domain tation in older than images?
Indeed at least not images um
no one seems to know I actually um I
Asked some of my friends in the natural language processing community about this. We'll get to natural language processing in a couple of lessons you
Know it seems like it'd be really helpful. There's been a few
Example I carry very few number examples of people where papers would like try replacing synonyms for instance
But on the whole and understanding of like appropriate data augmentation for non image domains is
Under-researched in under under developed
The question was could couldn't we just use a sliding window to generate on the images so in that dog
Thank you. Couldn't we generate three?
Parts of it wouldn't that be better. Yeah, PTI you mean?
Just just in general when you're creating your so
Training time I would say no that wouldn't be better because we're not gonna get as much variation
You know we want to have it like like
One degree off five you know five degrees off ten pixels up like lots of slightly different versions
And so if you just have three standard ways then you're not giving it as many different ways of looking at the data
for testing augmentation
Having fixed cropped locations. I think probably
Would be better
And I just haven't gotten around to writing that yet. I have a version in an old library. I think having fixed cropped locations
plus
random
Contrast brightness rotation changes might be better
The reason I've got around to it yet is because in my testing it didn't seem to help him practice very much
And it made the code a lot more complicated, so you know it's kind of it's an interesting question
I just wanted all of this last AI api's that you are using is it
Yeah, that's a great question so the faster you go libraries open source and let's talk about it a bit more generally because
You know it's like the fact that
The fact that we're using this library is kind of interesting and unusual
And it sits on top of something called a torch right so
pi torch is
a
fairly recent development
and it's kind of I've noticed all the
researchers that I respect pretty much are now using high torch I
Found in part two of last year's course that a lot of the cutting-edge stuff
I wanted to teach I couldn't do it in chaos and tensorflow, which is what we used to teach with
And so I had to switch the course to pay torch halfway through part two the problem was that
PI torch isn't very easy to use you have to write your own training loop from scratch
I basically write everything from scratch or the stuff you see inside the class they are library
We would have had to written it
You know to learn and so it really
makes it very hard to learn deep learning when you have to write hundreds of lines of code to do anything so
So we decided to create a library on top of Pi torch because we you know this
Our mission is to teach world class big morning
So we wanted to show you like here's how you can be the best in the world at doing it
And we found that a lot of the world class stuff we needed to show
really needed PI torch or at least with PI torch it was far easier and but then PI thought itself just wasn't suitable as a
first thing to teach with for new
For new deep learning practitioners, so we built this library on up of PI torch
Initially heavily influenced by chaos
Which is what we taught last year and but then we realized we could actually make things much much much easier than care us
So in care us if you look back at last year's course notes
You'll find that all of the code is two to three times longer
and there's lots more opportunities for
Stakes because there's just a lot of things you have to get right
So we ended up kind of building this this this library in order to make it easier to get into deep learning
but also easier to get state-of-the-art results and
Then over the last year as we started developing on top of that we started discovering that by using this library
It made us so much more productive that we actually started kind of developing you state-of-the-art results and new methods ourselves
And we started realizing that there's a whole bunch of like papers that have kind of been ignored or lost which
When you use them, it could like automate or semi-automated stuff like learning read finder. That's not in any other library, so
So it kind of got to the point where now not only is kind of fast AI
Lets us do things easier much easier than any other approach, but at the same time it actually
Has a lot more kind of sophisticated stuff behind the scenes than anything else so
So it's kind of an interesting mix
So yeah, so we've released this library like at this stage
It's like very early version and so through this course by the end of this course. I hope as a group
You know we will all a lot of people are already helping have developed it into something. That's
You know really pretty stable and rock-solid
And yeah, anybody can then can use it
To build your own models under an open-source license as you can see it's available on github
Behind the scenes it's it's creating play torch models and so apply torch models can then be exported
into various different formats
Having said that like a lot of folks like issue if you want to do something on a mobile phone for example
You're probably going to need to use tensorflow
and so
later on in this course
We're going to show like how some of the things that we're doing in the past AI library you can
do in chaos and cancel flow so you can going to get a sense of what the different libraries look like and
generally speaking the simple stuff
is
Like it'll take you a small number of days
To learn to do it and care us in tensorflow versus fast AI and high torch and the more complex stuff often
This won't be possible so that like if you needed to be intensive flow you're just kind of simplify it off in a little bit
But you know I think the more important thing to realize is
Every year the kind of the libraries that are available and which ones are the best totally changes so like the main thing
I hope that you get out of this course is an understanding of the concepts like here's how you find a learning rate?
Here's why differential learning rates are important is they do learn where the kneeling?
You know here's what stochastic gradient a second's restarts does so on and so forth?
Because you know by the time we do this course again next year
You know the library
situations and the difference the king
Was wondering if you've had an opinion on pyro which is ubers new release, I haven't looked at it
No, I'm very interested in probabilistic programming, and it's really cool
That's built on top of paper so one of the things we'll learn about in this course is we'll see that PI torch is much
More than just a deep learning library it actually lets us write arbitrary
Gpu-accelerated
algorithms
From scratch which we're actually going to do and pyro is a great example of what people are now doing with might watch
outside of the deep level
Great ok let's take a
Eight-minute break, and we'll come back at 7:55
So
Ninety nine point six five percent accuracy
What does that mean so in?
classification when we do classification and machine learning the
Really simple way to look at the result of a classification is what's called the confusion matrix
This is not just deep learning, but in any kind of classifier machine learning where we say okay. What was the actual truth there were?
thousand cats and a thousand dogs out of the thousand actual cats
How many did we predict were cats? This is obviously in the validation step?
This is the images that we didn't use to train with
It turns out there were nine hundred ninety-eight cats that we actually predicted as cats and two that we got wrong okay
And then for dogs there were nine hundred ninety-five that we predicted were dogs and then five that we got wrong and so often these
Confusion matrices can be helpful particularly if you've got like four or five classes you're trying to predict to see like which
group you having the most trouble with and you can see it uses color coding to
Tell you you know to highlight the large the large bits. You've got to hope that the diagonal is
the highlighted section
So now that we've retrained the model it can be quite helpful now
That's better to actually look back and see like okay, which ones in particular were incorrect and we can see here
There were actually only two incorrect cats
It prints out four by default so you can actually see these two actually less than 0.5
So they weren't they weren't wrong, okay, so it's actually these two were wrong cats and this one isn't obviously a cat at all
This one is but it looks like it's got a lot of weird artifacts, and you can't see its eyeballs at all so
and then here are the
How many dogs where they're all wrong there were five wrong dogs here are four of them? That's not obviously a dog
That looks like a mistake that looks like a mistake that one. I guess doesn't have enough information that I guess it's a mistake so
So we've done a pretty good job here of creating a good classifier. I would based on
Entering a lot of capital competitions and comparing results. I've done two various research papers
I can tell you it's a state of the art classifier. It's it's right up there with the best in the world
We're going to make it a little bit better in a moment
But here in the basic steps right so if you want to create a world-class image
Classifier the steps that we just went through was that we started our week's term data augmentation on
By saying oil transforms equals, and you either say sidon or top-down depending on what you're doing
Start with pre compute equals true
Find a decent learning eight we then train just like it one or two epochs
Which that takes a few seconds as we got through compute equals true?
Then we turn off pre compute, which allows us to use data augmentation to do another two or three epochs
generally with cycle length equals one
Then I unfreeze all them as I then set the earlier layers to be like
Either somewhere between a 3 times 2 10 times mobile learning rate in the previous so in this case I did
10 times right so it's like this was my learning rate that I found from the learning rate finer than I went 10 times smaller
and then 10 times smaller
as a rule of thumb like
knowing that you're starting with a pre trained imagenet model if
You know if you can see that the things that you're now trying to classify a pretty similar the kinds of things in imagenet ie
pictures of normal objects in normal environments
You probably want about a 10x difference because you want those earlier layers like you think that the earlier layers are probably very good already
But also if you're doing something like satellite imagery or medical imaging
Which is not at all like image net then you probably want to be training those earlier layers a lot more so you might have
like oh just a 3/8
Difference all right so that's like
One change that I make is to try to make it out of 10x or 3x
Yes, so then after unfreezing
You can now call LR find again, but at Nike didn't in this case
But like once you've unfrozen all the layers you've turned on differential learning rates. You can then call a lot of fine
again, right
And so you can then check like oh does it still look like the same point. I had last time is about right
Something to note is that if you call LR find
having set differential learning rates
The thing that's actually going to print out is the learning rate of the last layers right because you've got three different learning rates
So it's actually showing you the last layer
so then yeah
then I trained the full network with cycle more equals two and it'll either it starts with the fitting or I
Run out of time right so like let me show you all right, so let's do this again
A totally different data set so this morning
I noticed that some of you on the forums were playing around with this playground Kegel competition very similar
Called dog breed identification
So the dog breed identification cat will challenge
is
One where you don't actually have to decide which ones are cats and which ones the dogs
They're all dogs, but you have to decide what kind of dog. It is, but there are 120 different breeds of dogs
okay, so
You know obviously this could be like
different types of
Cells and pathology slides it could be different kinds of cancers in CT scans it could be
Different kinds of icebergs and satellite images whatever right as long as you've got some kind of labeled images
So I want to show you what I did this morning, so it took me about an hour
Basically to go in to end from something. I'd never seen before so I
Downloaded the data from kaggle, and I'll show you how to do that shortly, but the short answer
Is there's something called cable CLI?
Which is a github project you can search for and if you read the docs to basically run cagey download?
Provide the competition name and it will grab all the data for you to your crystal or Amazon or whatever instance
I put in my data folder
and
I then went LS and I saw that it's a little bit different to
Our previous data set it's not that there's a train folder
Which has a separate folder for each kind of dog?
But instead of tonette there was a CSV file and the CSV file I read it in with pandas
So pandas is the thing we use in python to do structured data analysis like csv files?
So he picked pandas. We called pd. That's pretty much universal
PDR htsb reads in the csv file we can then take a look at it
and you can see that basically it had like some kind of identifier and
Then the debris right so this is like a different way
This is the second main way that people kind of give you image labels one is to put different images into different folders
the second is generally to give you as some kind of file like a CSV file to tell you here's the image name and
here's the label, okay, so
What I then did was I used
Pandas again to create a pivot table, which basically groups it up
Just to see how many of each breed there were and I sorted them, and so I saw okay, they've got like about a hundred
some of the more common breeds and
Some of the less common breeds they've got like 60 or so okay?
Altogether there are 120 rows and I've been 120 different breeds represented, okay?
So I'm going to go through the steps right so
Enable data augmentation so to enable data augmentation when we call this transforms from model you just pass in and all
Transformers in this case I chose side on again. These are pictures of dots and stuff so this side on photos I
We're talking about maqsuum as
More detail later, but maximum basically says when you do the data augmentation we like zoom into it by up to
One point one times okay, so but randomly between one the original image size and one point one points
So it's not always cropping out in the middle or an edge, but it could be cropping out a smaller part, okay, so
Having done that the key step now is to graphically going from paths
So previously we went from paths and that tells it that the the names of the folders are the names of the labels we go
from CSV, and we pass in the
CSV file that contains the letters
So we're passing in the path that contains all of the data
The name of the folder that contains the training data the CSV that contains the labels
We need to also tell it where the test set is if you want to submit to cattle later talk more about that next week
now this time
The previous data set we had had actually separated a validation set out into a separate folder
Right, but in this case. You'll see that. There is not a separate folder called validation
right so
We want to be able to track how good our performance is low
So we're going to have to separate some of the images out to put it into a validation set
okay, so I do that at random and
So up here, you can see how it basically opened up the CSV file
Turned it into a list of rows and then taken the length of that
minus one because there's a header at the top right and so that's the number of
Rows in the CSV file which must be the number of images that we have and then this is a fast AI thing get cross-validation
Indexes now. We'll talk about cross-validation later, but basically if you call this and pass in a number. It's going to return to you
by default a random twenty percent of the rows who uses your validation set and you can pass in parameters to
get different amounts right so this is now going to grab twenty percent of the data and
Say all right. This is the this is the indexes the numbers of the files
Which we're going to use as a validation set, okay, so
Now that we've got that in fact let's kind of run this so you can see what that looks like
so
well
indexes is
Just a big bunch of numbers okay, and so an is
10,000 right and so we have about twenty percent of those is going to be in a validation set
So when we call?
From CSV
We can pass in a parameter, which is talent, which indexes to treat us a validation set and so that's passed in those indexes
One thing that's a little bit tricky here is that?
The
File names
Actually have I checked they actually have a dot jpg on the end and these obviously don't have a dot jpg
So you can pass in when you call from CSV you can pass in a suffix?
It says that the labels don't actually contain the full file names. You need to add this to them, okay
so
That's basically all I need to do to set up my data
And as a lot of Europe noticed during the week
Inside that data object you can actually get access to the data set like what the training data set by same train yes
And inside train des is a whole bunch of things including the file names
Okay
So train desktop file names contains all of the file names of everything in the training set and so here's like one file name
Okay, so here's an example of one file name
So I can now go ahead and open that file and take a look at it
That's the next thing I did was to try and understand what my file my dataset looks like and it found an adorable puppy
So that was very nice so feeling good about this
I also want to know like how big of these files right like how big are the images because?
That's a key issue if they're huge, and then I have to think really carefully about how to deal with huge images. That's really challenging
If they're tiny well that's also challenging
most of imagenet models are trained on either 224 by 224 or
299 by 299 images so anytime you have images in that kind of range
That's that's really hopeful. You're probably not going to have to do too much different in this case the first image
I looked at was about the right size, so I'm thinking of pretty hopeful
So what I did, then is I created a dictionary comprehension now if you don't know about list comprehensions and dictionary comprehensions in Python
Go study them. They're the most useful thing super handy
You can see the basic idea here
Is that are going through all of the files and then putting a dictionary that map's the name of the file to?
the size of that file
Again this is a handy little Python feature, which I'll let you think learn about during the week if you don't know about it
which is zip and using a special star notation is never to take this dictionary and turn it into the
rows and the columns
And so I can now turn those into num pay arrays and like okay. Here are the first five
rows sizes for each of my images and
Then matplotlib is something you want to be very familiar with if you do any kind of data science or machine learning in python
matplotlib we always refer to as PLT as if this is a histogram and so I got a histogram of the
How high how many rows there are in each image? So you can see here?
I'm kind of getting a sense before I start doing any modeling
I kind of need to know what I'm modeling with and I can see some of the images are going to be like
2500 3000 pixels high but most of them seem to be around 500
So given it so few of them were bigger than a thousand. I use standard numpy
Slicing to just grab those at a smaller than a thousand and histogram that
Just to zoom in a little bit, and I can see here all right
It looks like yet the vast majority are around 500 and so this actually also prints out
The histogram so I can actually go through and I can see here for four thousand five hundred of them are about 450 okay
So I get about that seems about anywhere
So generally how many images should we get in the validation set is always a 20%?
So the size of the validation set like
Using 20% is fine unless you kind of feeling like my data is my data. Sets really small. I'm not sure that's enough
You know like
if you've got
Basically think of it this way if you train like the same model multiple times
And you're getting very different validation set results and your validation sets kind of small but smaller than a thousand or so
Then it's going to be quite hard to interpret. How well you're doing now
This is particularly true like if you're like if you care about the third decimal place of accuracy
And you've got like a thousand things in your validation set then you bring about like a single image changing class is changing
You know it's what you're looking at so
it's it really depends on my cow accurate you have much difference you care about I
Would say in general like at the point where you care about difference between like out of 0.01 and 0.02 like the second decimal place
You want that to represent like?
10 or 20 roads you know like
Changing the class of that 10 or 20 rows then
That's something you can be pretty confident of
So like most of the time
You know give them the data sizes. We normally have 20 percent seems to work fine
But yeah, it's it's it's kind of a it depends a lot on
Specifically what you're doing and what you care about
And it's not it's not a deep learning specific question either
You know so those who are interested in this kind of thing we're going to look into it a lot more detail in our machine
learning course
which
Will also be available online
Ok so I did the same thing for the columns
Just to make sure that these aren't like super wide and I've got similar
Results and checked in and again found they're kind of like 4 or 500 seem to be about the average size
So based on all of that
I kind of thought ok this looks like a pretty normal kind of image data set that I can probably use pretty normal kinds of
models on I was also particularly encouraged to see that when I looked at the
That the dog like takes up most of the frame right, so I'm not too worried about like cropping problems. You know
If the if the dog was just like a tiny little piece of one little corner that I'd be thinking about doing different
You know maybe zooming in a lot more or something
Like a medical imaging that happens a lot like often the tumor or the cell whatever is like one tiny piece and there's much more
complex
So yeah based on all that and this morning. I kind of thought like okay
this looks pretty standard, so I
I
Went ahead and created a little function called get data that basically had my normal two lines of code in it
But I made it so I could passed in a size and a batch size
the reason for this is that when I start working with new data set I want everything to go super fast and
So if I use small images it's going to go super fast
So I actually started out with size equals 64
Just to create some super small images that just go like a second to run through and see how it
Later on I started using some big images and some and some also some bigger
Architectures at which point I started running out of GPU memory, so I started getting these errors saying
CUDA out of memory error when you get a CUDA out of memory error the first thing you need to do is to go kernel
restart once you get a code an out of memory error on your GPU you can't really recover from it right doesn't matter what you
Do you know you have to go restart?
And once I've restarted
I then just changed my batch size to something smaller so when you call create your data object
You can pass in a batch size parameter, okay?
And like I normally use 64 until I hit something that says out of memory
And then i'll just have it, and if I still get out of memory. I was hobbit again, okay
so that's where I created this to allow me to like start making my size as bigger as I looked into it more and
You know as I started running out of memory to decrease my batch size
so
at this point
You know I went through this a couple of iterations, but I basically found everything was working fine
So once it's working fine set size 2 to 24
and I
Created my you know pre-compute equals true first time
I did that it took a minute to create the precomputed activations
And then it ran through this in about 4 or 5 seconds, and you can see I was getting eighty-three percent accuracy
Now remember accuracy means, it's it's exactly right and so it's predicting out of a hundred and twenty categories
It's predicting exactly right so when you see something with two classes is you?
Know 80% accurate versus something with 120 classes is 80% accurate. They're very different
Levels you know so when I saw like eighty-three percent accuracy with just a pre computed classify and OData augmentation though
I'm freezing anything else across 120 classes of the oh this looks good right so um
Then I just kind of kept going throughout at all standard process right so then I turn
Precompute off
okay, and
Cycle length equals one, and I started doing a few more
Cycles few more epochs
so remember an epoch is one pass through the data and
a cycle is
However many epochs you said is in a cycle
It's one it's the learning rate going from the top that you asked for all the way down
So since here cycle length equals one a cycle in an epoch at the same. Okay, so I did I tried a few
epochs
I did actually do the learning rate finder, and I found one in a two again looked fine
It often looks fine, and I found it kind of kept improving so I tried five epochs, and I found my accuracy getting better
So then I saved that and I tried something which we haven't looked at before, but it's kind of cool
if you train something on a smaller size you can then actually call learned set data and
Pass in a larger size data set and that's gonna take your model however
It's trained so far and it's going to let you can in you to train on on
larger images
And I tell you something amazing
This actually is another way you can get state-of-the-art results and I've never seen this written in any paper
Or discussed anywhere as far as I know this is a new insight
Basically, I've got a pre trained model which in this case
I've trained a few epochs with the size of 224 by 224
And I'm now going to do a few more air pops with the size of 299 by 299 now
I've gotten very little data cut out by deep learning standards only about 10,000 images, right?
so with a 224 by 224
I kind of built this these final layers to try to find things that work well to 24 but to 24
but I go to 299 by 299 I
Basically if I over fit before I'm definitely not going to over fit now might have changed the size of my images
They're kind of like totally different
But like conceptually
They're still picked the same kinds of pictures are the same kinds of things so I found this trick of like starting training on small
Images for a few a box and then switching to bigger images and continuing training is an amazingly effective way to avoid
overfitting and
It's like it's so easy and so obvious
I don't understand why it's never been written about before maybe it's in some paper somewhere, and I haven't found it
But it's I haven't seen it
Would it be possible to do the same thing on using let's take a resort our
disposal to feed a
Different size yeah, I think so like as long as you use one of these more modern
Architectures what we call fully convolutional architectures, which means not vgg
and you'll see we don't use vgg in this course because it doesn't have this property but most of the
architectures developed in the last couple of years can handle pretty much arbitrary sizes
Yeah be worth trying yeah, I think it ought to work
Okay, so I call get data again remember get data is the just a little function that I created back up here right get data
Is just this little function that's oh, I just passed a different size to it
and so I
Call freeze just to make sure that but everything so the last layer is frozen
I mean it actually already was at its point that really doing a thing
and
You can see now with free compute off
I've now got that data augmentation working, so I kind of run a few more a pox and what I notice here
Is that the loss to my training set and the loss of my validation set my validation set loss is a lot lower than?
My training set this is still just training the last layer
so what this is telling me is I'm
Under fitting right and so from under fitting it means this cycle length equals one is too short
It means it's like finding something better popped with popping out and it's like never getting a chance to zoom in properly
So then I'd set cycle mod equals two to give it more time so like the first time is one epoch
The second one is two epochs the third one is for epochs
And you can see now the validation train and training are about the same
Okay, so that's kind of thinking. Yeah. This is this is about the right track and so then I tried using test time
Augmentation to see if that gets any better still didn't actually help a hell of a lot just a tiny bit
And just kind of at this point. I think here. This is nearly done
So I just did it like you know one more cycle of two to see if it got any better
And it did get a little bit better, and then I'm like okay
That looks pretty good. I've got a validation set
lost
0.199
And so your Lotus here
Actually, you haven't tried unfreezing the reason why I was going to try to unfreezing and training more
It didn't get any better and so the reason for this clearly is that this data
set is so similar the image net that the training that convolutional layers actually doesn't help in the slightest and
actually when I loaded up into it it turns out that this competition is actually using a
Subset of improve image net so that's okay so that if we check this out point one nine nine
against the leaderboard
This is only a playground competition, so it's not like the best of here, but you know it's still interesting
It gets us
Somewhere around ten thrillers, okay, and
In fact we're competing against. I noticed other the first AI student. This is a first AI student
These people up here. I know they actually posted that they cheated. They actually went you downloaded the original images and train to that so
And this is why this is a playground competition they call it. It's not it's not real right you know
It's just to allow us to try things out, but you can basically see
Out of two hundred and something people where you know we're getting some very good results
Without doing anything remotely interesting or clever
and we haven't even used the whole data set you're going to use to eighty percent of it like to get a better result I
Would go back and remove that validation set and just rerun the same steps and then submit that exact
Let's just use it under percent of the data
Have three questions the first one is like that class in this case is very it's not balanced
Instead unbalanced like it's not totally balanced, but it's not bad right. It's like
Between sixty and a hundred like it's it's it's it's not unbalanced enough that I would give it a second thought okay?
Yeah, let's get to that later in this course and don't let me forget right the short answer is that there was a recent list
The paper came out about two or three weeks ago on this
and it said the best way to deal with very unbalanced data sets is to basically make copies of the
rare cases
Yeah, my second question is I want to pin down a difference between creation he read was and
So you have these two options right so when you beginning I
Did an optimization use that pre computed it was true by not using layers
Right right so it's not only they frozen their pre computed so the data augmentation doesn't do anything at that point
Right before you outcries everything
What as examples you and IV only you only on freeze?
So we're going to learn more about the details as we look into the the math and stuff in coming lessons
But basically what happened was we started with a pre trained network, right?
Which was kind of finding activations that had these kind of rich features?
And we were adding, then we add a couple of layers on the end of it
Which which start out random and so with fries equals?
with with everything frozen and indeed with pre compute equals true all we're learning is told is those couple of layers that we've added and
So with pre compute equals true
We actually pretty
Calculate like how much does this image have something that looks like this a ball one looks like this face and so forth
and therefore data augmentation doesn't do anything with pre compute equals true because
You know we're actually showing exactly the same activations each time we can then set pre compute equals false
Which means it's still only training those last two layers that we added
It's still frozen, but data augmentations now working because it's actually going through and recalculating all of the activations from scratch
And then finally when we unfreeze that's actually saying okay, now. You can go ahead and change all of these earlier
convolutional filters, so well you just
So the only reason to have pre compute equals true is it's just much faster, so it's like it is
It's about you know ten or more times faster, so particularly if you're working with like quite a large data set
You know it can save quite a bit of time, but it's never
There's no like companies like
Accuracy reason ever to use pre computed calls true. It's just a it's just a shortcut. It's also like quite handy. If you're like
Throwing together a quick model you know it can take a few seconds to create
My last question, which I think you answer is I
Don't like your suggestions to build a model you have this aged yeah
What if
Would you like we just wanted one?
Initial setting without these like checking after each
I mean if you want it like if your question is like is there some shorter version of this
That's like a bit quicker and easier. I could like to lead a few things here
Okay, I think this is a kind of a minimal version to get you a very good result which is like
don't worry about pre compute equals true because that's just saving a little bit of time you know so so I
Still suggest use LR find at the start to find a good learning rate
By default everything is frozen from the start so then you can just go ahead and run two or three epochs or cyclic Nichols one
unfreeze
And then train the rest of the network with differential learning rates, so it's basically three steps learning rate finder
Trained frozen network with cycle methods one and
Then trained unfrozen network with differential learning rates and cycle molecules, too
so like that's something you could turn into I
guess five or six lines of code
at all I
Think it's a question provide your own mix book
By reusing the batch size does the only at better speed of training yeah?
Pretty much so each batch and again
We're going to see like all this stuff about precomputing batch sizes we dig into the details of the algorithms
It's going to make a lot more. Sense intuitively, but basically if you're showing it
Less images each time then it's calculating the gradient with less images
Which means it's less accurate which means like knowing which direction to go and how far to go in that direction
Is less accurate so as you make the batch size smaller you're basically making it kind of more volatile
It's kind of like
It kind of impacts the
Optimal learning rate that you would need to use but in practice where only you know
I generally find only dividing with the batch size by like 2 or 4 it doesn't seem to change things very much
Should I reveals the learning rate of quality me?
If you if you change the batch size by much you can rerun the learning rate finder to see if it's changed if I match
But it it
I was in for only
Generally looking at like a power of 10 it probably is not going to change the it's not that you can't because plus back there
This is sort of a conceptual
Basic questions, we're going back to the previous night where you should put in the thought behind, sorry yeah
This is well one for conceptual so a basic question. We've actually really slide where you should what the different layers were doing?
Yes from this slide I understand right the meaning of
sync the third column relative to the fourth column is that
What you're interpreting what the layer is doing based on what the image is actually?
Yeah, so we're going to look at this in more detail
So these these gray ones basically say this is kind of what the filter looks like so on the first layer
You can see exactly what the filter looks like because the input to it of pixels
Right so you can absolutely say and remember we looked at what a convolutional kernel was like was that three by three thing
So this look like there's seven by seven kernels you can say this is actually what it looks like but later on
It's combined. You know the the the input to it are themselves
Activations which are combinations of activations relation to activations so you can't draw it
But there's clever technique that I learned focus created which allowed them to say
This is kind of what the filters tended to look like on average
Alright, so this is kind of what the photos look like and then here is specific examples of patches of image which?
Activated that filter highly so yet the pictures are the ones that I kind of find more useful because it tells you this
Kernel is kind of a mini cycle. We all find
Right how do we know that's it?
Well we'll come back well we may come back to that if not in this part in the next part that
Probably a part two actually because this paper this paper uses to create these things this paper uses something called a deconvolution
Which I'm pretty sure we won't do in this part, but we will do it in part two so if you're interested
Check out the paper. It's it's in the notebook has a link to it xyler in Fergus
It's a very clever technique
And not terribly intuitive
So you mentioned that it was good that the dog took up the full picture
And it would have been a problem if it was kind of like off in one of the corners in really tiny
Well, what would you what would you technique have been to try to make that work?
Something that we'll learn about in part two but basically
There's a technique that allows you to to kind of
figure out roughly which parts of an image and most likely to have the interesting things in them and
Then you can like crop out those bits if you're interested in learning about it
We did cover it briefly in lesson seven of part one, but I'm going to actually do it
properly in part two of this course
Because I didn't really cover it thoroughly enough
Maybe we'll find time to have a quick look at it
But we'll see I know your Nets written some of the code that we need already
So once I have something like this notebook. That's basically working I can
Immediately make it better by doing two things
assuming that the size image
I was using is smaller than the average size of the image that we've been given I can increase the size and
As I showed before with the dog breeds you can actually increase it during training
The other thing I can do is to create is to use a better
Architecture now an architect. We're going to talk a lot in this course about architectures, but basically
there are
Different ways of putting together like what size convolutional filters, and how are they connected to each other and so forth?
and
Different architectures have different like numbers of layers and sizes of kernels and number of filters and so forth and so
There are some the one that we've been using ResNet 34 is a great
Starting point and often a good finishing point because it's like it's pretty it doesn't have too many parameters often
It works pretty well with small amounts of data as we've seen and so forth but
There's actually an architecture that I really like called not res net but res next
Which was actually the second-place winner in last year's image net competition?
and
Like ResNet you can put a number after the res next to say like how big it is and
Like my next step after resume 34 is always res next 50 now
you'll find res next 50 takes like can take like twice as long as
ResNet 34 that can take like 2 to 4 times as much memory as retina 34
so what I wanted to do was I wanted to rerun that previous notebook with res next and
Increasing the image size to turn on a node so here
I just said architecture equals res next 50 size equals 299
And then I found that I had to take the batch size all the way back to 28 to get it to fit my GPU
Is 11 gig if you're using AWS or cresol? I think they're like?
12 gigs they might be a bit higher
But this is what I found I had to do so then I this is literally a copy of the previous notebook
So you can actually go file make a copy?
right and then rerun it with with these different parameters and
So I deleted some of the pros and some of the expiratory stuff to see you know basically
I said everything else is the same all the same steps as before there's my in fact
You can kind of see what this minimum service desk looks like I didn't need to worry about learning rate finder
So I just left it as is so
transforms data equals loan equals bit pre computed false feet with cycle integrals one and
freeze
differential learning rates
Bits and more and you can see here
I didn't do the cycle mop thing because I found like now that I'm using a bigger architecture. It's got more parameters
It was overfitting
Pretty quickly so rather than like cycle length equals one never finding the right spot it actually did find the right spot
and if I used longer cycle legs I found that my
Validation error was higher than my training error. It was over there
So check us out though by using these you know
Three steps, I got plus TTA
99.75
So what does that mean that means? I have one incorrect dog for incorrect cats and when we look at the pictures of them
My incorrect dog has a cat now this one is not a either this one is not either so I've actually got one
mistake and then my incorrect dog is
teeth
Right so like we're at a point
Where we're now able to train a classifier, that's so good that it has like
Basically one's dead
Right and so when people say like we have superhuman image performance now
This is kind of what they're talking about right, so did you actually when I looked at the?
Dog breed one. I did this morning. I was like it was it was getting the dog breeds much better than I ever could
So like hits this this is what we can get to if you use a really modern architect like redneck
And this suddenly took out a tall way and remember don't like 20 minutes to Train
If you want to do
satellite imagery instead
Right then it's the same thing and in fact the the planet satellite data sets already
oh and Chris, or if you're using Chris or you can jump straight there right and
I just went into this data stash planet, and I can do exactly the same thing right I can
Image classifier from CSV
Right and you can see these three lines are actually exactly the same as my dog breed lines
You know how big how many lines are in the file grab my validation indexes?
This get data as you can see it's identical except. I've changed
Side on to top down the satellite images about top down so I can fit them
Vertically and they still make sense right and so you can see here. I'm doing this trick round back to size equals 64 and
Train a little bit first learning rate find on right and interestingly in this case you can see it
I want really high learning rates I
Don't know what it is about this particular data
Set this is true, but it's clearly I can use super high learning rate, so I use a lot here at a point, too
And so I've trained for a while
differential learning rates right and so remember
I said like if the data sets very different to image net I probably want to train those middle layers a lot more
so I'm using divided by three rather than divided by ten all right the other than that is the same thing cycle Nauticals -
All right
and
Then I just kind of keep an eye on it
So you can actually plot the loss if you go and learned up shared a plot loss
You can see here that here's the first cycle
Is the second cycle?
Is the third cycle right so you can see it gets better?
Pops out gets better pops out if better pops out and each time it finds something better than the last time
Then set the size up to 128 and just repeat exactly the last few steps and then set up to 256
repeat the last two steps and then
Do TTA and if you submit this and this gets about 30th place in this competition?
so these basic steps work super well this this thing where I went all the way back to a size of 64 I
Wouldn't do that if I was doing like dogs and cats or dog breeds because like this is so small that
if if the thing I was working on is very similar to imagenet I would kind of
Destroy those imagenet weights like 64 by 64 is so small but in this case the satellite imagery data
It's so different to imagenet. Um you know I really found that it worked pretty well start right back to these tiny images
It really helped me to avoid overfitting
and interestingly
Using this kind of approach I actually found that even with using only 128 by 128
I was getting like much better cackled results than really everybody on the leader board and when I say 30th place
This is a very recent competition right and so I find like in
The last year like a lot of people have got a lot better at computer vision and so the people in the top 50 in
This competition were generally ensemble in dozens of models lots of people on a team
lots of pre-processing specific satellite data
And so forth so like to be able to get xxx using this totally standard technique is pretty cool
Alright
So now that we've got to this point right. We've got through two lessons if you're still here then hopefully you're thinking
Okay, this is actually pretty useful
I want to do more in which case Kressel might not be where you want to stay the issues with Kressel
I mean, it's it's it's pretty handy. It's pretty cheap and something we haven't talked about much is paper
Space is another great choice by the way paper. Space are short. They're going to be releasing kress or like instant Drupal. Notebooks unfortunately
They're not ready quite yet
but they do have an ability to
Basically, they have the best price
performance relationship right now and they you can SSH into them and use them so
They're also a great choice and probably by the time this the MOOC
Will probably have a separate lesson
Showing you how to set up set up paper space because there they're likely to be a great option
but at some point you're probably going to want to look at AWS a
Couple of reasons why the first is as you all know by now
amazon have been kind enough to donate about
$200,000 worth of compute time to this course, so I want to say thank you very much to Amazon
We've all been given credit, so everybody this year, so thanks very much. Hey, don't worry. We're
So sorry you're sure in the MOOC. We didn't get it for you, but everybody here is like
AWS credits for everybody so um
But you can get even if you're not here in person you can get AWS credits from lots of places
Github has a student pack Google for github student pack. That's like 150 bucks worth of credits
AWS educate can get credits these our office students, so there's lots of places you can get started on AWS
pretty much everybody
Everybody a lot of the people that you might work with
Will be using AWS
Because it's like super flexible
Right now AWS has the fastest available GPUs you can get in the cloud. They're p3s
They're kind of expensive at three bucks an hour
But if you've got like a model where you've done all the steps before you're thinking. This is looking pretty good
You know for 6 bucks you could get a p3 for 2 hours and run
turbo speed right
Um we didn't start with AWS because well. Hey it's like twice as expensive as Chris Hall for the cheapest GPU
And being a Texan setup, right
But I wanted to kind of go through and show you how to get your AWS setup
And so we're going to be going slightly over time to do that
But I want to show you a very quick place. I feel prettier if you have to
But I want to show you very quickly how you can get your
AWS setup right from scratch so
Basically you have to go to consult on AWS but
Amazon.com and it'll take you to the console right and so you can follow along on the video with this
quickly from here you have to go to
AC - this is where you set up your instances and so from ec2
You need to do what's called launching an instance so launching an instance means you're basically creating a computer
right now creating a computer on Amazon, so I say launch instance and
what we've done is we've created a fast AI it's got an amo and ami is like a
template for how your computer's going to begin so if you've got a community a Mis and type in fast AI
You'll see that. There's one there called fast AI part 1 version 2 for the p2
ok so I'm going to select that and
then we need to say what kind of computer do you want and so I can say I want a GPU compute computer and
Then I can say I want a p2 x large. This is the cheapest
Reasonably effective for deep learning instance type they have and then I can say launch
and
then I can say launch and
So at this point they asked you to choose a key pair right now
If you don't have a key pair you have to create one right?
So to create a key pair
You need to open your terminal
If you don't have a terminal if you've got a Mac or Linux box you've definitely got one if you've got Windows
Hopefully you've got Ubuntu
if you don't already have Ubuntu setup, you can go to the Windows Store and
Click on
Ubuntu right we'll get it from the Windows Store
So from there you basically go SSH
- caged in and
That will create like a special password for your computer to be able to log in to Amazon
And then you just hit enter three times
Okay, and that's going to create for you your key, you can use to get into Amazon alright
So then what I do is I copy that key somewhere that I know where it is, so it'll be in the dot SSH folder
It's called IDRs a dub and so I'm going to copy it
to
My hard drive
So if you're in a macro and Linux it'll already be in an easy to find place it'll be in your SSH folder
That in documents
So from there back in AWS you have to tell it that you've created. This key, so you can go to key pairs and
You say import key pair, and you just browse to that file that you just created
There it is I say import
Okay, so if you've ever used SSH before you've already got the key pair
You don't have to do those depths if you've used AWS before you've already imported it. You don't have to do that step
Maybe haven't done any of those things you have to do both steps
So now I can go ahead and launch my instance
Community I am eyes search last day I
Select
launch and
So now it asks me
what's where's your key pair, and I can choose that one that I just
grabbed okay
So this is going to go ahead and create a new computer for me to log into
And you can see here. It says the following have been initiated, and so if I click on that
It'll show me
This new computer that I've created okay
So it'll be able to log into it
I need to know its IP address
So here it is the IP address there. Okay, so I can copy that and
That's the IP address of my computer
so to get to this computer I need to
SSH to it so SSH into a computer means connecting to that computer so that it's like you're typing in that computer
So I type SSH and they username
For this instance is always Ubuntu
Right and then I can paste in that IP address, and then there's one more thing
I have to do which is I have to connect up the jupiter notebook on that instance to the jupiter notebook on my machine and
So to do that there's just a particular
Flag that I said, okay, we can talk about it on the forums as to exactly what it does
But you just type - l.a today date
localhost 8 8 8 8 ok so like once you've done it once you can like save that as an alias and type in the
same thing every time
So we can check here, we can see it says that it's running so we should be able to now hit enter
First time ever which sit reconnect to it. It does checks. This is okay. I'll say yes
And then that goes ahead and SSH is in
So
This ami is all set up for you alright
So you'll find that the very first time you log in it takes a few extra seconds because it just kind of is getting everything
Set up
But once it's logged in you'll see there that there's a directory called fast AI
And the fast AI directory contains our fast AI repo that contains all the notebooks
Or the code etc so I can just go CD faster
All right first thing you do when you get in is to make sure it's updated, so you just go git pull
right and that updates
to make sure that your repo is the same as the most recent video and
So as you can see there we go
Let's make sure it's got all the most recent code the second thing you should do is type Condor and update
You can just do this maybe once a month or so and that makes sure that the libraries there are all the most recent
Libraries I'm not going to run that so it takes a couple of minutes okay, and then the last step is to type particular notebook
Okay, so this is going to go ahead and launch the triplet notebook
Server on this machine again the first time I do it the first time you do everything on AWS
It just takes like a minute or two
And then once you've done it in the future. We just as fast as running it locally basically
Okay, so you can see it's going ahead and firing out the notebook
And so what's going to happen is that because when we SSH into it? We said to both connect our?
Notebook port to the remote notebook port we're just going to be able to
Use this locally so I see he says here copy paste this URL
so I'm going to grab that URL and
I'm going to paste it into my browser and
That's it, okay, so this notebook is now actually not running on my machine. It's actually running on AWS
Okay, using the AWS GPU it's got a lot of memory. It's not the fastest around, but it's not terrible
You can always fire up a p3 if you want something that's super fast. This is costing me ninety cents a minute
Okay, so when you're finished. Please don't forget to shut it down right so to shut it down
You can
right-click on it and
Say instance date
stop
Okay
We've got five hundred bucks of credit
Assuming that you put your code down in the spreadsheet?
One thing I forgot to do the first time I showed you this by the way. I said make sure you choose a
p2
The second time I went through I didn't choose p2 by mistake, so just don't forget choose gpq compute P
- do you have a question
My Bernice it's an hour. Thank you
90 cents an hour
It also costs like I don't know three or four bucks a month for the storage as well
Thanks for checking that all right. See you next week. Sorry. We're a bit over