Hi everybody welcome to practical deep learning for coders
this is part one of our two-part course, I'm
Presenting this from the data Institute in San Francisco
Will be doing seven lessons in this part of the course
Most of them will be about a couple of hours long this first one may be a little bit shorter
Practical deep learning for coders is all about getting you up and running with deep learning in practice getting world-class results
And it's a really coding focused approach as the name suggests
But we're not going to dumb it down by the end of the course you all have learned all of the
Theory in details that are necessary to rebuild all of the world-class results. We're learning about from scratch
Now I should mention that our videos are hosted on YouTube
That we strongly recommend watching them via our website. At course.fast.ai
although they're exactly the same videos the important thing about watching them through our website is that you'll get all of the information
You need about kind of updates to libraries my own locations
further information frequently asked questions and so forth
So if you're currently on YouTube watching this why don't you switch over to crosstalk fast at AI?
Now and start watching through there and make sure you read all of the material
On the page before you start just to make sure that you've got everything you need
The other thing to mention is that there is a really great strong community at forums faster I
From time to time you will find that you get stuck
You may get stuck very early on you may not get stuck for quite a while
But at some point you might get stuck with understanding
Why something works the way it does or there may be some computer problem that you have or so forth?
On forums.fast.at AI there are thousands of other learners talking about every lesson and lots of other topics besides
It's the most active deep learning community on the internet by far so definitely register there
And start getting involved you'll get a lot more out of this course if you do that
So we're going to start
By doing some coding. This is an approach. We're going to be talking about in the moment called the top-down approach to study
But let's learn it by doing it, so let's go ahead and try and actually train a neural network
Now in order to train a neural network. You almost certainly want a GPU
GPU of is a graphics processing a graphics processing unit
It's the things that
Companies use to help you play games better
They let your computer render the game much more quickly than your CPU okay
We'll be talking about them more shortly, but for now I'm going to show you how you can get access to a GPU
Specifically you're going to need an NVIDIA GPU because only NVIDIA GPUs support something called cooter
Cooter is the language and framework that nearly all deep learning
Libraries and practitioners use to do their work
Obviously, it's not ideal that we're stuck with one particular vendors cards and over time we hope to see more competition in this base
But for now we do need an NVIDIA GPU
Your laptop almost certainly doesn't have one unless you specifically went out of your way to buy like a gaming laptop
So
Almost certainly you will need to rent one and the good news is that renting access
Paying by the second or a GPU based computer is pretty easy and pretty cheap
I'm going to show you a couple of options
The first option, I'll show you which is
Probably the easiest is called Kressel
if you go to kress allcom and
Click on sign up, or if you've been there before sign-in
You will find yourself at this screen
which has a big button that says start jupiter and
another switch called enable GP you so if we make sure that is set to true the Nabal GPU is on and
We click start Jupiter
and
It's going to launch us into something called Jupiter notebook
Jupiter notebook in a
Recent survey of tens of thousands of data scientists was rated as the third most important tool in the data scientist toolbox
It's really important that you get to learn it well and all of our courses will be run through Jupiter
Yes, Rachel, you have a question or a comment
I just wanted to point out that you get I believe 10 free hours, so if you wanted to try Cresyl out
Yeah, He might have changed that recently to less hours, but you can check the FAQ or the pricing but you certainly get some free hours
The pricing varies because this is actually runs on top of Amazon Web Services so at the moment. It's 60 cents an hour
The nice thing is though that you can always turn it turn it on you know start your Jupiter without the CP without the GPU
Running and pay you a tenth of that price which is pretty cool
So Jupiter notebook is something we'll be doing all of this course in and so to get started here
we're going to find our particular course, so we're go to courses and
would go to fast a o2
and
there they are
Things have been moving around a little bit so it may be in a different spot for you
When you look at this and we'll make sure all the information current information is on the website
Now having said that that's you know the crystal approach is
You know as you can see it's basically instant and and easy
but if you've got
You know an extra hour or so to get going and even better option is something called paper space
Paper space unlike Chris, or doesn't run on top of Amazon. They have their own machines
And
if I click on so here's here's paper space and so if I click on new machine I
can pick which one of the three data centers to use so pick that one closest to you, so I'll say a West Coast and
Then I'll say Linux, and I'll say Ubuntu 16
And then it says choose machine and you can see there's various different machines I can choose from
and
pay-by-the-hour
So this is pretty cool for 40 cents an hour, so it's cheaper than cresol. I get a machine
That's actually going to be much faster than Crescent 67 our machine or for 65 cents an hour way way way faster
All right, so I'm going to actually show you how to get started with
The paper space approach because that actually is going to do everything from scratch
You may find if you trailers do the 65 cents an hour one that it may require you to contact paper space to say
Like why do you want it, and it's just an anti fraud the thing so if you say faster AI there
then
They'll quickly get you up and running so I'm going to use the cheapest one here 40 cents an hour
You can pick how much draw it you want and
Note that you pay for a month of storage as soon as you start the machine up alright
so don't start and stop lots of machines because each time you pay for that month of storage I
Think the 250 gig $7 a month option is pretty good
But you only need 50 gig so if you're trying to minimize the price you can go there
The only other thing you need to do is turn on public IP so that we can actually log into this and
We can turn off auto snapshot to save the money or not having backups
All right, so if you then click on create your paper space about a minute later you will find
That your machine will pop up here is my Ubuntu 1604 machine
If you check your email
You will find that they have emailed you a password so you can copy that and
You can go to your machine and enter your password
Now to paste the password you would press ctrl shift V or on Mac against Apple shift V
So it's slightly different to normal pasting or of course you can just type it in
And here we are now we can make a little bit more room here by clicking on those little arrows
There can zoom in a little bit
And so as you can see we've got like a terminal. That's sitting inside
Our browser it's just kind of quite a handy way to do it
So now we need to configure this further course and so the way you can figure it for the course is you type
Curl
HTTP colon slash slash files dot fast ai slash setup slash paper space
Type
-
Okay, and so, that's then going to run a script which is going to set up all of the crudo drivers
Special Python
Reaper Python distribution we use called anaconda all of the libraries or other courses
And the data we use for the first part of the course ok so that takes an hour or so and when it's finished running
You'll need to reboot your computer
So to reboot not your own computer
But your pages paste computer and so to do that you can just click on this little circular
Restart machine button ok and when it comes back up you'll be ready to go so what you'll find
Is if you've now got an anaconda three directory
That's where your python is you've got a data directory which contains the data for the first part of this course
first lesson which is their dogs and cats
And you've got a fast AI directory
and that
Contains everything for this course
So what you should do?
is
CD fast AI and from time to time you should go get Paul and that will just make sure that all of your
Fast AI stuff is up-to-date
And also from time to time you might want to just check that your Python libraries are up-to-date
And so you can type Condor and update?
to do that
Alright, so make sure that you've CD into fast AI and then you can type Jupiter
notebook
All right there, it is so we now have a Jupiter notebook servant running
And we want to connect to that and so you can see here. It says copy paste this URL
Into your browser when you connect so if you double click on it
Then that will actually
That will actually copy it for you
Then you can go and paste it, but you need to change this local host
To be the paper space IP address so if you click on the little arrows to go smaller you can see the IP addresses here
so I'll just copy that and
Paste it
Where it used to say local host okay, so it's now HTTP and then my IP and then everything else a copied before
And so there it is
So this is the faster I?
get repo and our courses are all in courses and
in there the deep learning part one is DL one and
In there you will find
lesson one by Mb ipython notebook
So here we are ready to go depending whether you're using Kressel or paper space or something else if you check course
It's not fast today. I will keep putting additional videos and links to information about how to set up other
You know good Jupiter notebook?
Providers as well
So to run a cell in Jupiter notebook you select the cell and you
hold down shift and press Enter or
If you've got the tool bar showing you can just click on the little Run button so you'll notice that some cells contain
Code and some contain text and some contain pictures and some contain videos so this environment basically has
You know it's a it's a way that we can give you access to and a way to run experiments
And to kind of tell you what's going on so pictures
This is why it's like a super popular
Tool in data science a data science is kind of all about running experiments really
So let's go ahead and click run and
You'll see that cell turn into a star the one turn into a star for a moment, and then it finished running, okay
So let's try the next one this time instead of using the toolbar. I'm going to hold down shift and press ENTER
And you can see again it turn into a star and then it said to
So if I hold down shift and keep pressing enter it just keeps running each, so
Right so I can put anything. I like for example one plus one is
two
so
What we're going to do is we're going to
Yes, Rachel. This is just a side note, but I wanted to point out that we're using Python 3 here
Yes, Thank you. Pythons are still using Python - mmhmm. Yeah
um and it is important to switch to Python 3
You know now well for Class A. I you require it
But you know increasingly a lot of libraries are
removing support for Python 2.
Thanks Rachel
Now it mentions here that you can download the data set for this lesson from this location
if you're using
Crystal or the paper space script that we just used to set up that this will already be and made available for you
Okay, if you're not you'll need to "wget" it as
now
Kressel is
Quite a bit slower than paper space and also it
There are some particular things
It doesn't support
That we really need and so there are a couple of extra steps if you're using cresol you have to run two more cells
Right so you can see these are commented out there quite hashes at the start
So if you remove the hashes from these and run these two additional cells
That just runs the stuff that the stuff that you only need for crystal. I'm using paperspace, so I'm not going to run it.
ok so
Inside our
Data, so we set up this path to data slash dogs cats
That's pre. Set up for you, and so inside there. You can see here. I can use an exclamation mark
to
Basically say I don't want to run Python, but I want to run bash, right
I want to run shell so this runs a bash command and the bit inside the curly brackets
Actually refers however to a python variable so inserts that python variable into the batch command
So here's the contents of our folder?
There's a training set and a validation set if you're not familiar with the idea of training sets and validation sets
It would be a very good idea to check out our
practical "Machine Learning" course
Which tells you a lot about this kind of stuff if like yeah the basics of how to setup and run
machine learning projects more generally
Would you recommend that people take that course before this one?
Actually a lot of students who would you know as they went through these as said? They'll they've liked doing them together?
so you can kind of check it out and see
the machine learning course
Yeah, they cover with some similar stuff, but all in different directions
So people have done both seen you know say they find it they they each support each other. I wouldn't say it's a prerequisite
But you know if I do if I say something like hey
This is the training set and this is a validation set and you're going
I don't know what that means at least Google, but do a quick read you know because we're assuming that
You know the very basics of kind of what machine learning is and does to some extent
And I have a whole blog post on this topic as well, okay
And we'll make sure that you link to that from cource.fast.ai
And as we just wanted to say in general with fasting our philosophy is to kind of learn things on an as-needed
Basis yeah exactly don't try and learn everything that you think you might need first, otherwise
You'll never get around elite learning the stuff you actually want to learn exactly that shows up in deep learning, I think
Particularly a lot yes
okay, so
in our validation folder
There's a "cats" folder and a "dogs" folder and then inside the validation cats folder is a whole bunch of JPEGs
The reason that it's set up like this is that this is kind of the most common standard approach for how?
image classification
Datasets shared and provided and the idea is that each folder tells you the label
So there's each of these
Images is labeled cats and each of the images and the dogs folder is labelled dogs, okay?
This is how Keras works as well for example
So, this is a pretty standard way to share image classification
Files
So we can have a look so if you go plot dot a.m.. Show we can see an example of the first of the cats
If you haven't seen
This before this is a Python
3.6. Format string so you can google for that if you haven't seen it
It's a very convenient way to do string formatting and we use it a lot
So there's no cat, but we're going to mainly be interested in the underlying data that makes up that cat
so specifically
It's an image whose shape that is the dimensions of the array is 198 by 1/7 9x3 is it's a three dimensional?
Array plus a quarter rank three tensor
and here are the first four rows and four columns of that image, so
as you can see
each of those
cells has three
Items in it
and this is the red green and blue pixel values between naught and 255 so here's a little subset of what a
Picture actually looks like inside your computer
so that's that that's will be our idea is to take these kinds of numbers and
Use them to predict whether those kinds of numbers represent a cat or a dog
based on looking at lots of pictures of cats and dogs
So that's a pretty hard thing to do and at the point in time when this
this this data set actually comes from a caracal competition the dogs versus cats caracal competition and
When it was released in I think it was 2012
The state of the art was 80% accuracy so computers weren't really able to
at all accurately recognize dogs versus cats
So let's go ahead and train a model
So
Here are the three lines of code necessary to train a model
And so let's go ahead and run it so I'll click on this on the cell. I'll press shift enter
and
Then we'll wait a couple of seconds for it to pop up and there it goes
okay, and it's training and
So I've asked it to do three epochs so that means it's going to look at every image
Three times in total or look at the entire set of images three times
That's what we mean by an epoch, and as we do. It's going to print out
the
Accuracy is that's lasted for three numbers it prints out on the validation set okay?
The first three numbers we'll talk about later in short
They're the value of the loss function which is in this case the cross-entropy loss?
For the training set and the validation set and then right at the start here is the epoch number
So you can see it's getting about
90% see
And it took 17 seconds so you can see we've come a long way since
2012 and in fact even in the competition
This actually would have won the caracal competition of that time the best in the caracal competition was 98.9 and we're getting about
99%
so this play surprised you that we're getting a
You know Kaggle winning as of 20 and of 2012 early 2013
Kaggle winning image classifier in 17 seconds
That and three lines of code
And I think that's because like a lot of people assume that deep learning takes a huge amount of time
And lots of resources and lots of data, and as you'll learn in this course
That in general rule isn't true
One of the ways, we've made it much simpler is that this code is written on top of a library we built
imaginatively called fast AI
The faster a library is basically a library which takes all of the
Best practices approaches that we can find and so each time a paper comes out you know we that looks interesting we test it out
If it works well for a variety of data sets and we can figure out how to tune it we implement it in fast AI
And so faster, I kind of curates all this stuff and packages up for you and much of the time
but most the time kind of
Automatically figures out the best way to handle things
So the first day our library is why we were able to do this in just three lines of code
And the reason that we were able to make the faster. I library work, so well is because it interns
It's on top of something called pi torch
Which is a?
really flexible
Deep learning and machine learning and GPU computation library written by Facebook
Most people are more familiar with tensorflow than pi torch because google markets that pretty heavily but
Most of the top researchers I know nowadays at least the ones that are at Google have switched across to PI torch yes, Rachel
And we'll be covering some pie torts later in the course. Yeah, it's I mean one of the things that
Hopefully you'll really like about last AI is that it's really flexible that you can use all these kind of curated best
Practices as much as little as you want and so really easy to hook in at any point and write your own
Data augmentation write your own loss function write your own network architecture whatever and so we'll do all of those things
in this course
So what does this model look like?
Well what we can do is we can take
A look at so what are the what is the validation set?
Dependent variable the Y look like and it's just a bunch of zeros and ones okay
So the zeros if we look at data dot classes the zeros represent cats the ones represent dogs. You'll see here
There's basically two objects
I'm working with one is an object called data, which contains the validation and training data
And another one is the object called learn which contains the model, right?
So anytime you want to find something out about the data. We can look inside data
So we're going to get predictions through our validation set and so to do that we can call learned predict
and
So you can see here the first ten predictions and what it's giving you as a prediction for dog and a prediction for cat
Now the way PI Torche generally works and therefore fast AI also works. Is that most models return the
log
Of the predictions rather than the probabilities themselves we'll learn why that is later in the course
So for now recognize that to get your probabilities you have to get
e to the power of
You'll see here. We're using
Numpy NP is none play if you're not familiar with numpy
That is one of the things that we assume that you have some familiarity with
So be sure to check out the material on cost I passed at AI to learn the basics of number
It's the way that - handles all of the
Fast numerical programming
Array computation that kind of thing
Okay, so we can get the probabilities using that
using MP dot X
And there's a few functions here that you can look at yourself if you're interested. That's just some flooding functions that we'll use
And so we can now plot some random correct
Images and so here are some images that it's correct about okay
and so remember one is a dog so anything greater than 0.5 is dog and
Zero is a cat, so this is what 10 to the negative 5 obviously a cat
here are some which are
Incorrect alright so you can see that some of these which it thinks are incorrect obviously are just
The you know images that shouldn't be there at all
But clearly this one, which it called a a dog is not at all a dog. So there are some obvious mistakes
We can also take a look at
Which cats is it the most confident are cats, which dogs are the most doglike the most confident dogs
Perhaps more interestingly we can also see which cats is that the most confident are actually dogs
So which ones it is it the most wrong about and?
same thing for
The ones the dog said it really thinks of cats and again some of these are just
Pretty weird, I guess. There is a dog in there. Yes, Rachel
I see suit you want to see more about why you would want to look at your data
Yeah, sure
So yeah, so finally, I just mentioned the last one. We've got here is to see which ones have the probability closest to 0.5
so these are the ones that the
Model knows it doesn't really know what to do with and some of these it's not surprising
So yeah, I mean, this is kind of like
Always the first thing I do after I build a model is to try to find a way to like visualize what it's built
Because if I want to make the model better
Then I need to take advantage of the things that's doing well and fix the things that's doing badly and so in this case
And off this is the case I've learned something about the data set itself
Which is that? There are some things that are in here that probably shouldn't be?
But I've also like it's also clear that
this
Model has room to improve
Like to me. That's pretty obviously a
Dog but one thing I'm suspicious about here is
This image is very
kind of fat and
short
And as we all learn
The way these algorithms work is it kind of grabs a square piece at a time?
So this rather makes me suspicious that we're going to need to use something called data augmentation that we'll learn about
Learn about later to handle this properly
Okay, so
That's it, right we've now built
We've now
Built an image classifier and something that you should try now is to grab some data yourself
Some pictures of
Two or more different types of thing put them in different folders and run the same three lines of code
On them okay, and you'll find
That it will work for that as well as long as that they are pictures of things like
The kinds of things that people normally take photos of right so if their
microscope microscope pictures or pathology pictures or
CT scans or something this won't work very well as well learn about later. There are some other things
We didn't need to do to make that work, but for things that look like normal photos
These you can run exactly the same three lines of code
and just point your
path variable somewhere else
To get your own image classifier so for example
one student
Took those three lines of code
Downloaded for Google Images ten examples of pictures of people playing cricket ten examples of people playing baseball
And build a classifier
Of those images which was new perfectly correct
the same
student actually also tried downloading seven pictures of
Canadian currency seven pictures of American currency and again in that case
the model was a hundred percent accurate so you can just go to Google Images if you like and
Download a few things of a few different classes and see see what works and tell us on the forum
both your successes and your failures
So what we just did was to
Train a neural network, but we didn't first of all tell you what a neural network is or what training means or?
anything
Why is that well this is the start of our?
top-down approach to learning
And basically the idea is that unlike the way math and technical subjects I usually talk
where you learn every little element piece by piece, and you don't actually get to put them all together and
Build your own image classifier until third year of graduate school our approach is to say
From the start hey, let's show you how to train an image classifier
And you can start doing stuff and then gradually we dig deeper and deeper and deeper
and
So the idea is that?
Throughout the course you're going to see like new problems that we want to solve so for example in the next lesson
We'll look at well
What if we're not looking at normal kinds of photos, but we're looking at satellite images
And we'll see why it is that this approach that we're learning today doesn't quite work as well and what?
things do we have to change and so we'll learn enough about the theory to understand why that happens and then we'll learn about the
Libraries and how we can change change things with the libraries to make that work better
and
So during the course we are gradually going to learn to solve more and more problems as we do so we all need to learn
More and more parts of the library more and more bits of the theory until by the end
we're actually going to learn how to create a
world plus neural net
Architecture from scratch and our own training loop from scratch and so were actually built everything ourselves
So that's the general
approach
Yes, Rachel, and sometimes also call this the whole game which is inspired by harvard professor
david perkins yeah
And so the idea with the whole game is like this is more like how you would learn baseball
Or music with baseball you would get taken to a ball game
You would learn what baseball is you would start playing it?
And it would only be years later that you might learn about the physics of how curveball works for example
Well with music we put a instrument in your hand and you start banging the drum or hitting the xylophone
And it's not until years later that you learn about the circle of fifths and understand how to construct a cadence example
So yeah, so that this is kind of the approach. We're using it's very inspired by
David Perkins and other writers of Education
So what that does mean is to take advantage of this as we peel back the layers?
we want you to keep like looking under the hood yourself as well like experiment a
Lot now because this is a very code driven approach
so here's basically what happens right we start out looking today at
convolutional neural networks for images and then in a couple of lessons
We'll start to look at how to use neural nets to look at structured data, and then look at language data
and then look at recommendation system data and
Then we kind of then take all of those depths and we go backwards through them in reverse order
So now you know by the end of that fourth piece you will know
By the end of lesson four how to create a world-class image classifier a world-class
structured data analysis program
world-class language classifier broad class recommendation system
And then we're going to go back over all of them again and learn in depth about like well
What exactly did it do and how to do work and how do we change things around and use it in different situations for?
for recommendation systems structured data
Images and then finally back to language so that's how it's going to work
So what that kind of means is that most students find that they tend to watch the videos two or three times?
but not
Like watch lesson one two or three times and listen to two or three times in verse and three three times
But like they do the whole thing into end lessons one through seven and then go back and start lesson one again
That's an approach which a lot of people find when they want to go back and understand all the details
Enough that can work pretty well, so I would say you know aim to get through to the end of lesson seven
You know as as quickly as you can rather than aiming to fully understand every detail from this data
So basically the plan is that in today's lesson you'll learn
In as few lines of code as possible with as few details as possible
How do you actually build an image classifier with deep learning to do this to in this case say?
Hey, here are some pictures of dogs as opposed to pictures of cats
Then we're going to learn
how to look at different kinds of images
And particularly we're going to look at images of from satellites, and we're going to say for a satellite image
What kinds of things might you be seeing in that image and there could be multiple things that we're looking at so a multi-label classification
problem
From there. We'll move to something which is perhaps the most
Widely applicable for the most people which is looking at what we call structured data
So data about data that kind of comes from
databases or spreadsheets
So we're going to specifically look at this data. Set of predicting sales the number of things that are sold at different stores
on different dates
Based on different holidays and and so on and so forth and so we're going to be doing its sales forecasting exercise
After that we're going to look at language, and we're going to figure out
What this person?
Thinks about the movie is on be given
And will be able to figure out how to create just like we create image
Classifiers for any kind of image will learn to create in NLP classifiers to classify any kind of language in lots of different ways
Then we'll look at something called collaborative filtering which is used mainly for recommendation systems
We're going to be looking at this data set that showed four different people
For different movies what rating did they give it and here are some of the movies and so?
This is maybe an easier way to think about it
Is there are lots of different users and?
lots of different movies and
Then for each one we can look up for each user how much they liked that movie and the goal will be of course to
predict for user movie combinations
We haven't seen before are they likely to enjoy that movie or not and that's the really common approach used for like
Deciding what stuff to put on your homepage when somebody's visiting?
You know what book might they want to read or what film might they want to see or so forth?
From there we could have then dig back into language a bit more, and we're going to look at
Actually, we're gonna look at the writings of Nietzsche the philosopher and learn how to create our own
Nietzsche philosophy from scratch character by character
So this here perhaps that every life values a blood of intercourse when it senses. There is unscrupulous
Who's very right sense to impulse love is not actually Nietzsche?
That's actually like some character by character
Generated text that we built with this recurrent neural network
And then finally we're going to loop all the way back to computer vision again
We're going to learn how not just to recognize cats from dogs how to actually find like where the cat is
With this kind of hate map, and we're also going to learn how to write our own architectures from scratch
So this is an example of a resonate
Which is the kind of network that we are using in today's lesson for computer vision?
And so we'll actually end up building the network and the training loop from scratch
And so they're basically the the steps that we're going to be taking from here
And at each step, we're going to be getting into
Increasing amounts of detail about how to actually do these things yourself
So we've actually heard that from our students of past courses
about what they've found and
one of the things that we've heard a lot of students say is that there's been too much time on theory and
research
And not enough time running the code
And even after we tell people about this morning where they still come to the end of the course not and say
I wish I had taken more seriously
That advice which is to keep running code?
So these are actual quotes from our forum in retrospect
I should have spent the majority of my time on the actual code, and the notebooks
See what goes in see what comes out
Now this idea that you can create
World-class models in a code first approach learning what you need as you go is very different to a lot of the advice
You're read out there such as this
Person on the forum hacker news who claimed that the best way to become an m/l engineer is to learn
all of math and C and C++
learn parallel programming learn ml algorithms implement them yourself using plain C and
Finally start doing ml so we would say if you want to become an effective practitioner do exactly the opposite of of this
Yes, Rachel. Yeah, I'm just highlighting that this is
We think this is bad advice and this can be very discouraging for a lot of people to come across this yeah
yeah, it's it's it's it's you know we now have thousands and more tens of thousands of people that have done this course and
have
Lots and lots of examples of people who are now running?
research labs or
Google brain residence or you know have created patents based on deep learning and so forth who have done it by doing this course
So the top-down approach works
super well
Now one thing to mention is like we've we've now already learned how you can actually train a
World-class image classifier in 17 seconds I should mention by the way the first time you run that code
there are two things it has to do that take more than 17 seconds one is that it downloads a
Pre trained model from the internet, so you'll see the first time you run it. It'll say downloading model
So that takes a minute or two?
also
The first time you run it it pre computes and caches some of the intermediate information that it needs
And that takes about a minute and a half as well so if the first time you run it it takes
three or four minutes
To download and pre compute stuff that's normal if you run it again. You should find it takes 20 seconds or so
so
image classifiers
You know you may not feel like you
Need to recognize cats versus dogs very often on a computer. You can probably do it yourself pretty well, but what's interestingly?
Interesting is that these?
Image classification algorithms are really useful for lots and lots of things
For example
Alphago, which became which beat the go world champion the way it worked was to use something
At its heart that looked almost exactly like our dogs vs. Cats image classification algorithm
It looked at thousands and thousands of go boards
And at for each one there was a label saying whether that go board ended up being the winning or the losing
Player and so it learnt
basically an image classification
That was able to look at a go board and figure out whether it was a good group or a bad code board
And that's really the key most important step in playing Gowell is to know which which move is better
Another example is one of our earlier students who actually
Got a couple of patterns for this work
Looked at anti-fraud he had lots of
All of his customers mouths movements because they they provided kind of these
User tracking software to help avoid fraud, and so he took the the mouse paths
basically of the users on his customers websites
Turn them into pictures of where their mouse moved and how quickly it moved
And then built a image classifier that took those images
As input and as output it was was that a fraudulent transaction or not
And turned out to go. You know really great results for his company so image classifiers are
Like much more flexible than you might imagine
so
So this is how you know some of the ways you can use deep learning specifically for image recognition and
It's worth understanding that
Deep learning is not
You know just a word that means the same thing as machine learning
Right like what is it that we're actually doing here when we're doing deep learning
Instead deep learning is a kind of machine learning
So machine learning was invented by this guy Arthur Samuels who was pretty amazing in the late 50s?
He got this IBM mainframe to play checkers
Better than he can and the way he did it was he invented machine learning. He got the
Mainframe to play against itself lots of times and figure out which kinds of things led to victories and which kinds of things didn't
And use that to kind of almost write its own program
And Arthur Arthur Samuels actually said in 1962 that he thought that one day
The vast majority of computer software would be written
Using this machine learning approach rather than written by hand by writing the loops and so forth by hand
So I guess that hasn't happened yet, but it seems to be in the process of happening
I think one of the reasons it didn't happen for a long time is because traditional machine learning actually was very
difficult and very
Knowledge and time intensive so for example. Here's something called the computational pathologist or C path
from backwater and II back and II back back when he was at Stanford
He's now moved on to
somewhere on the East Coast no Harvard, I think
And what he did was he took these pathology slides of breast cancer
biopsies right and
he worked with lots of
pathologists to come up with ideas about what kinds of
patterns or features might be associated with so long-term survival versus
Versus dying quickly basically and so he came up with these ideas like well
They came up with these ideas like relationship between epithelial nuclear neighbors
Relationship between epithelial and stromal objects and so forth and so they came up with all of these ideas of features
These are just a few of the hundreds that they thought of and then lots of
smart computer programmers wrote
Specialist algorithms to to calculate all these different features and then those those
Features were passed into a logistic regression to predict survival, and it ended up working very well
And it ended up that the survival predictions were more accurate than pathologists own survival predictions work
and so machine learning can work really well, but the point here is that this was a
An approach that took lots of domain experts and computer experts
Many years of work to actually to build this thing right?
so
We really want something
something better
And so specifically I'm going to show you something which rather than being a very specific
function with all this very domain-specific
Feature engineering
We're going to try and create an infinitely flexible function a function that could solve any problem
Right it would solve any problem
If only you set the parameters of that function correctly
And so then we need or purpose way of setting the parameters of that function
And we would need that to be fast and scalable
Right now if we had something that had these three things
Then you wouldn't need to do this incredibly time and domain knowledge intensive approach anymore
Instead we can learn all of those things
with this
with this algorithm
So as you might have guessed
The algorithm in question, which has these three properties is called deep learning
Or it's not an algorithm then maybe we will call it a class of algorithms
Let's look at each of these three things in turn
So the underlying function that deep learning uses is something called the neural network
Now the neural network. We're going to learn all about it and implemented ourselves from scratch later on in the course
But for now all you need to know about it. Is that it consists of a number of simple linear layers
interspersed with a number of simple nonlinear layers
And when you in dispersed these layers in this way
You get something called the universal approximation theorem and the universal approximation theorem says that
This kind of function
Can solve any given problem?
To arbitrarily close accuracy as long as you add enough parameters
So it's actually provably shown to be an infinitely flexible function
okay, so now we need some way to fit the parameters so that this infinitely flexible neural network solves some specific problem and
So the way we do that is using a technique that
Probably most of you will have come across before at some stage called gradient descent and with gradient descent
We basically say okay well for the different parameters. We have
how how good are they at solving my problem and
Let's figure out a slightly better set of parameters and a slightly better set of parameters and j6v follow down
The the surface of the loss function downwards it's kind of like a marble going down
find the minimum and
As you can see here depending on where you start you end up in different places
These things a court local minima now interestingly it turns out that for neural networks particularly in particular
There aren't actually multiple different
Local minima there's basically just
There's basically just one right or think of it another way there are different parts of the space which are all equally good
so
Gradient descent therefore turns out to be actually an excellent way to
Solve this problem of fitting parameters to neural networks
The problem is though that we need to do it in a reasonable amount of time and
It's really only thanks to GPUs that that's become possible
So GPUs this shows over the last few years
How many gigaflops per second can you get out of a
GPU that's the red and green versus a CPU that's the blue right and this is on a log scale so
You can see that generally speaking
the GPUs are
about 10 times faster than the CPUs
and
What's really interesting is that nowadays not only is the?
Titan X about 10 times faster than the e5 to $6.99 CPU
But the Titan X. Well actually better one to look at would be the GTX 1080i
GPU costs about 700 bucks
Whereas the CPU which is 10 times slower costs over $4,000?
So GPUs turn out to be able to solve these
Neural network parameter fitting problems
incredibly quickly
And also incredibly cheaply, so they've been absolutely key in bringing these three pieces together
Then there's one more piece
Which is I mentioned that these neural network so you can intersperse multiple sets of linear and then nonlinear layers?
In the particular example, that's drawn here
there's actually only one what we call hidden layer one layer in the middle and
Something that we learned in the last few years is that these kinds of neural networks, although they do
Support the universal approximation theorem they can solve any given problem arbitrarily closely
They require an exponentially increasing
number of parameters to do so so they don't actually solve the fast and scalable for even reasonable size problems
But we've since discovered that if you create add multiple hidden layers
Then you get super linear scaling so you can add a few more hidden layers to get
multiplicatively
more accuracy 2ma duplicative lis more complex problems and
That is where it becomes called deep learning, so deep learning means a neural network with multiple hidden layers
So when you put all this together, there's actually really amazing what happens
Google started investing in deep learning in 2012
They actually hired Geoffrey Hinton who's kind of the father of deep learning and his top student Alex Bogusky?
and they started trying to build a team that team became known as Google brain and
because
Things with these three properties are so incredibly powerful and so incredibly flexible
You can actually see over time how many projects at Google?
Use deep learning
My graph here only goes up through a bit over a year ago
But it's I know it's been continuing to grow exponentially since then as well
And so what you see now is around Google that deep learning is used in like every part of the business
And so it's really interesting to see how
The this kind of simple idea that we can solve machine learning problems using a an
Algorithm that has these properties
When a big company invests heavily in actually making that happen
You see this incredible growth in how much it's used
So for example if you use the inbox by Google software
Then when you receive an email from somebody it will often
Tell you here are some replies
That I could send for you and so it's actually using deep learning here to read the original email and to generate
some suggested replies
And so like this is a really great example of the kind of stuff that
Previously just wasn't possible
Another great example would be Microsoft is also a little bit more recently
Invested heavily in deep learning and so now you can
Use Skype you can speaking to it in English and ask it at the other end to
Translate it in real time to Chinese or Spanish and then when they talk back to you in Chinese or Spanish Scott will in real-time
Translated the speech in in their language into English speech in real-time
And again, this is an example of stuff which we can only do thanks to deep learning
And something is really interesting to think about how deep learning can be combined with
human expertise
So here's an example of low drawing something just sketching it out, and then using a program called neural doodle
This is from a couple of years ago - then say, please take that sketch and render it in the style of an artist
And so here's the picture that have been created
Rendering it as you know impressionist painting, and I think this is a really great example of how?
You can use deep learning to help combine human expertise and what computers are good at
So I a few years ago decided to try this myself like what would happen if I took
Think learning and tried to use it to solve a really important problem and so the problem. I picked was
Diagnosing lung cancer it turns out if you can find
lung nodules earlier
There's a 10 times higher probability of survival
So it's a really important problem to solve so I got together with three other people none of us had any medical background
And we grabbed a data set of CT scans
We used to compilation or neural network
Much like the dogs vs. Cats one. We trained at the start of today's lesson
to try and predict which
CT scans had
malignant tumors in them
And we ended up after a couple of months with something with a much lower
false negative rate and a much lower false positive rate than a panel with four radiologists
and we went on to build this in a start-up in just into a company called analytic, which has really become pretty successful and
Since that time the idea of using deep learning for medical imaging has become
Hugely popular and is being used all around the world so
What I've generally noticed is that you know the vast majority of
Of kind of things that people do in the world currently aren't using deep learning and then each time somebody says oh
Let's try using deep learning to improve performance at this thing
They nearly always get fantastic results and then suddenly everybody in that industry starts using it as well
So there's just lots and lots of opportunities here at this particular time
To use deep learning to help with all kinds of different stuff, so
I've jotted down a few ideas here. These are all things which I know you can use
Deep learning for right now to get good results from
and
You know are things, which people spend a lot of money on or have a lot of you know important business opportunities
There's lots more as well
That these are some examples of things that maybe your company you could think about applying deep learning for
So let's talk about what's actually going on?
What actually happened when we trained that deep learning model earlier and?
so as I briefly mentioned the thing we created is something called a convolutional neural network or CNN and
The key piece of a convolutional neural network is the convolution
So here's a great example from our website
I've got the URL up here
explained visually
It's called and the explained visually website has an example of a convolution
kind of in fact this over here in the bottom left is a very zoomed in picture of somebody's face and
Over here on the right is an example of using a convolution on that image you
Can see here this particular thing is obviously finding?
the eges of his head about top and bottom edges in particular
Now how is it doing that? well, if we look at each of these are all three by three areas. This is moving over
It's taking each three by three area of pixels and here are the pixel values
right for each thing in that 3x3 area and
It's multiplying each one of those 3 by 3 pixels by each one of these
3 by 3
kernel values in a convolution this specific set of
9 values is called a kernel it doesn't have to be 9,
it could be 4 by 4 or 5 by 5 or 2 by 2 or whatever right?
In this case it's a 3 by 3 kernel and in fact a deep learning nearly all of our kernels are 3 by 3
so in this case the kernel is 1, 2, 1, 0, 0, 0, -1, - 2, -1, so we take each of the
Black through white pixel values and we multiply as you can see each of them by the corresponding value in the kernel
and then we add them all together and
so if you do that for every 3x3 area
You end up with the values you see over here on the right hand side
Okay, so very low values become
black very high values become white and so you can see when we're at an edge
Where it's black at the bottom and white at the top?
We're obviously going to get higher numbers over here and vice versa okay, so that's a convolution
So as you can see it is a linear operation and so based on that definition of a neural net I described before
This can be a layer in our neural network
It is a simple linear operation
And we're going to look much more at convolutions later including building a little spreadsheet that implements them ourselves
so the next thing we're going to do is we're going to add a
nonlinear layer
so a non-linearity as it's called is something which takes an input value and
turns it into some different value in a nonlinear way, and you can see this orange picture here is an example of a
nonlinear function
specifically, this is something called a sigmoid and
So a sigmoid is something that has this kind of S-shape,
and this is what we used to use as our nonlinearities in neural networks a lot actually nowadays
We're nearly entirely use something else called a rally or rectified linear unit
A rail u is simply take any negative numbers and replace them with 0 and
Leave any positive numbers as they are so in other words in code. That would be
Y equals max X comma 0 so max X comma 0 simply says
replace the negatives with 0
Now regardless of whether you use a sigmoid or a ReLU you or something else
The key point about taking this combination of a linear layer followed by a element-wise
nonlinear function is that it allows us to create arbitrarily complex shapes as you see in the bottom right and
The reason why is that and this is all from Michael Nelson's neural networks and deep learning com really fantastic
Interactive book as you change the values of your linear functions
It basically allows you to kind of like
Build these arbitrarily tall or thin blocks and then combine those blocks together
And this is actually the essence of the universal approximation theorem this idea that when you have a linear layer
Feeding into a non-linearity you can actually create these arbitrarily complex shapes
So this is the key idea behind, why neural networks can solve any computable problem
So then we need a way as we described to actually
Set these parameters, so it's all very well knowing that we can move three a meters around manually to try to
create different shapes
But we have some specific shape we want how do we get to that shape and?
So as we've discussed earlier the basic idea is to use something called gradient descent
This is an extract from a notebook actually one of the first AI lessons
and it shows actually an example of using gradient descent to
solve a simple linear regression problem
But I can show you the basic idea. Let's say you were just you had a simple
Quadratic all right and
So you are trying to find?
The minimum of this quadratic and so in order to find the minimum you start out by randomly picking
Some point all right, so we say okay. Let's pick
Let's pick here, and so you go up there, and you calculate the value of your quadratic at that point
So what you now want to do is try to find a slightly better point?
So what you could do is you can move a little bit to the left and a little bit to the right?
To find out which direction is down, and what you'll find out is that moving a little bit to the left
Decreases the value of the function so that looks good and so in other words, we're calculating the derivative
There's a function at that point
Right so that tells you which way is down
It's the gradient and so now that we know that going to the left is down. We can take a small step in that direction
To create a new point, and then we can repeat the process and say okay
Which way is down now and we can now take another step and another step and another step another step another step, okay?
And each time we're getting closer and closer
So the basic approach here is to say okay? We start. We're at some point
We've got some value X. Which is our current guess right. That's at time step n
So then our new guess at time step n plus 1 is. Just equal to our previous guess
plus
the derivative
Right times
Some small number because we want to take a small step
We need to pick a small number because if we picked a big number, right
Then we say okay, we know we want to go to the left. Let's jump a big long way to the left
we could go all the way over here and
We actually end up worse all right, and then we do it again
Now we're even worse again right so
if you have too high a
step size
You can actually end up with divergence rather than convergence so this number here
We're going to be talking about it a lot during this course
And we're going to be writing all this stuff out in code from scratch ourselves, but this number here is called the learning rate
Okay, so
You can see here
This is an example of basically starting out with some random line and then using gradient descent to gradually make the line better and better
and better
So what happens when you combine these ideas right the convolution?
The non-linearity and gradient descent because they're all tiny small simple little things it doesn't sound that exciting
but if you have enough of
These kernels right
with enough layers something really interesting happens
And we can actually draw them
So here's the
So, this is a really interesting paper by Matt Siler and Rob Fergus and what they did a few years ago
was they figured out how to basically draw a picture of what each layer in a deep learning net Network learned and
So they showed that layer one of the network here are nine
examples of convolutional filters from layer one of a trained network
and they found that some of the filters kind of learnt these diagonal lines or
Simple dat or grid patterns some of them learnt these simple gradients right and so for each of these filters
They show nine examples of little pieces
Of actual photos which activate that filter quite highly right so you can see layer one
These learnt or ever these these are learnt using gradient descent these filters were not programmed
They will learnt using gradient descent so in other words we were learning
These nine numbers
So layer two then was going to take these as inputs and
Combine them together and
So layer two
Had you know this is like my in kind of attempts to draw one of the examples of the filters in layer two
They're pretty hard to draw, but what you can do is say if the each filter
What are examples of little bits of images that activated them, and you can see by layer two? We've got?
Basically something that's being activated nearly entirely by little bits of sunset some things that's being activated by
circular objects
something that's being activated by
Repeating horizontal lines something that's being activated by corners
So you can see how we're basically combining layer one features together
So if we combine those features together and again these are all
Convolutional filters won't through gradient descent by the third layer
It's actually learn to recognize the presence of text
Another filter has learnt to recognize the presence of petals
Another filter has learnt to recognize the presence of human faces right so just three layers is enough to get some pretty
Rich behavior so but by the time we get to layer five
We've got something that can recognize the eyeballs of insects and birds and something that can recognize
Unicycle wheels alright so so this is kind of where we start with something
incredibly simple right
But if we use it as a big enough scale
Thanks to the universal approximation theorem and the use of multiple hidden layers in deep learning
We actually get the very very rich
capabilities
So that is what we used when we actually trained
Our little dog vs. Cat recognizer, okay?
So
Let's talk more about this dog vs cat recognizer
So we've learnt the idea of like we can look at the pictures that come out of the other end to see what the model
Is classifying well like as I find badly or which ones it's unsure about
But let's talk about like this key thing
I mentioned which is the learning rate so I mentioned we have to set this thing
I just caught it L before the learning rate, and you might have noticed. There's a couple of numbers these kind of magic numbers
Here the first one is the learning rate
Right so this number is how much do you want to multiply the gradient by when you're taking each step?
in your gradient descent
We already talked about why you wouldn't want it to be too high
Right, but probably also. It's obvious to see why you wouldn't want it to be too low if you had it too low
You would take like a little step, and you'd be a little bit closer and little bits
too little step little step, and it would take lots and lots and lots of steps, and it would take too long so
Setting this number well is actually really important and for the longest time this was driving
deep learning researchers crazy because they didn't really know a
Good way to set this reliably
so the good news is last year
a researcher came up
With an approach to quite reliably set the learning rate
Unfortunately almost nobody noticed so almost no deep learning researchers. I know about actually are aware of this approach
But it's incredibly successful, and it's incredibly simple
And I'll show you the idea right it's built into the fast AI library as something called @lr find or the learning rate finder
And it comes from this paper. I was actually 2015 paper, sorry
cyclic or learning rates for training neural networks by a terrific researcher called Leslie Smith and
I'll show you Leslie's idea
So Leslie's ideas started out with the same
Basic idea that we've seen before which is if we're going to optimize something pick some random point
Take its gradient
All right, and then specifically he said take a tiny tiny step
Like tiny step so a learning rate of like 10 e next seven all right, and then do it again again
But each time increase the learning rate like double it so then we try like to wean X 7 14 X 7
18 X 7
10 in X 6 right and so gradually
your steps are
getting bigger and bigger
Right and so you can see what's going to happen. It's gonna like
Start doing almost nothing right and it's going to then suddenly the loss function is going to improve very quickly
Right, but then it's going to step even further again
And then even further again
All right, let's draw the rest of that line to be clear
All right, and so suddenly it's then going to shoot off and get much worse
right so
the idea then
Is to go back and say okay?
At what point did we see like the best improvement
So here
We've got our best improvement right and so I would say ok. Let's use that
Learning rate right so in other words if we were to plot
the learning rate
Over time
It was increasing
like so
Alright, and so what we then want to do is we want to plot
the learning rate
against the loss
Right so when I say the loss
I basically mean like how accurate is the model how close in this case the loss would be how far away is the?
predictive prediction
from the goal, okay?
And so if we plotted the learning rate against the loss we'd say like okay, initially it didn't do very much
right
for small learning rates, and then it suddenly improved a lot and
Then it suddenly got a lot worse
So that's the basic idea, and so we'd be looking for the point where this graph is
Dropping quickly right we're not looking for its minimum point
We're not saying like where was it the lowest because that could actually be the point where it's just jumped too far
We want at what point was it dropping the fastest?
So if you go
So if you create your learn object in the same way that we did before we'll be learning more about this these details shortly
if you then call lr_find method on that you'll see that it'll start training a
Model like it did before but it'll generally stop before it gets to 100% okay because if it notices
That the loss is getting a lot worse
Then it'll stop automatically that's what you can see here
It stopped at 84% and so then you can call one said that gets you the learning rate scheduler
That's the object which actually does this learning rate finding and that object has a plot learning rate function and so you can see here
Over by iteration you can see the learning rate alright, so you can see each step the learning rate is getting bigger and bigger
You can do it this way we can see it's increasing exponentially another way that Leslie Smith the researcher suggests is to do it linearly
So I'm actually currently researching with both of these approaches to see which works best
Recently I've been mainly using exponential, but I'm starting to look more using Linea at the moment
And so if we then call shed but plot that does the plot that I just described down here
learning rate
Versus loss all right, and so we're looking for the highest learning rate we can find
Where the loss is still improving?
Clearly well right and so in this case I would say
10 to the negative 2x that 10 to the negative 1. It's not improving
Right 10 to the negative 3 it is also improving, but I'm trying to find the highest learning rate
I can or it's still clearly improving, so I'd say 10 to the negative 2
Okay, so you might have noticed that when we ran our model before?
We had
10 to the negative 2, 0.01.
so that's why we picked that learning rate
So there's really only one other number that we have to pick and
That was this number three and so that number three controlled how many
epochs did we run so an epoch means going through our entire data set of images and
Using each each time we do a bunch of they're called mini batches we grab like
64 images at a time and use them to try to improve the model a little bit using gradient descent
Right and using all of the images once is called one epoch
and so at the end of each epoch we print out the accuracy and
validation and training loss at the end of the epoch
so
the question of
How many epochs should be run?
is kind of the one other question that you need to answer to run these three lines of code and
The answer really to me is like
as many as you like.
What you might find happen is if you run it for too long the accuracy you'll start getting worse all right
And we'll learn about that why later it's something called overfitting right so
You can run it for a while run lots of epochs
Once you see it getting worse
you know how many epochs you can run and the other thing that might happen is if you've got like a really big model or
a lot lots and lots of data, maybe it takes so long you don't have time and so you just run enough epochs that
Fit into the time you have available so the number of epochs you run. You know that's a pretty easy thing to set
So there are the only two numbers you're gonna have to see it
And so the goal this week will be to make sure that you can run
Not only these three lines of code on the data that I provided
But to run it on a set of images that you either have on your computer or that you get from work
Well that you download from Google
And like try to get a sense of like which kinds of images. This is seem to work well for
Which ones doesn't it work well for?
What kind of learning rates do you need for different kinds of images how many epochs Do you need
how does the number of the learning rate change the accuracy you get and so forth like really experiment and then?
You know try to get a sense of  what's inside this data object. You know
What are the y-values look like what are these places mean if you're not familiar with numpy?
You know really practice a lot with numpy so that by the time you come back for the next lesson
You know we're going to be digging into a lot more detail, and so you'll really feel ready to do that now
one thing that's really important to be able to do that is that you need to really know how to
work with
Numpy, the fastai library, and so forth. and so I want to show you some tricks in Jupiter notebook to make that much easier
So one trick to be aware of is if you can't quite remember how to spell something right so if you're not quite sure
What the method you want is you can always hit tab and you'll get a list of?
Methods that start with that letter right and so that's a quick way to find things
If you then can't remember what the arguments are to a method hit shift tab
All right
so hitting shift tab
Tells you the arguments to the method so shift tab is like one of the most helpful things I know
So let's take  "np.exp"
Shift tab and so now you might be wondering like okay
Well, what does this function do and how does it work if you press shift tab twice?
Then it actually brings up the documentation
shows you what the parameters are and
Shows you what it returns
And gives you examples
Okay, if you press it three times
Then it actually pops up a whole little separate window with that information. Okay, so shift tab is super helpful!
One way to grab that window straight away is if you just put question mark at the start
Then it just brings up that little documentation window
Now the other thing to be aware of is increasingly during this course
We're going to be looking at the actual source code of fast AI itself and learning how it's built and why it's built that way
It's really helpful to look at source code in order to
Understand what you can do
And how you can do it so if you for example wanted to look at the source code for learned
I predict you can just put two question marks
Okay, and you can see it's popped up the source code right and so it's just a single line of code
You're very often find that fast AI methods like they they're designed to never be more than about
Half a screen full of code, and they're often under six lines, so you can see this case it's calling predicted with tags
So we could then get the source code for that in the same way
Okay
and then that's calling a function called predicted with tags so we could get that documentation for that in the same way and
Then so here, yeah
And then finally that's what it does it either rates through a data loader gets the predictions and then passes them back
and so forth, okay, so
"??" is how to get source code, but the single question mark is how to get documentation
and
Shift-tab is how to bring up parameters, or press it more times
to get the docs
So that's really helpful another really helpful thing to know about is how to use?
Jupiter notebook well and the button that you want to know is H
If you press H. It will bring up the keyboard shortcuts
Palette and so now you can see exactly what Jupiter notebook can do and how to do it
I personally find all of these functions useful
So I generally tell students to try and learn four or five different keyboard shortcuts a day
Try them out see what they do see how they work, and then you can try practicing in that session
And one very important thing to remember when you're finished with your work for the day
Go back to a paper space and click on that little button
Which stops and starts the machine so after it's stopped?
You'll see it says connection closed and you'll see it's off if you leave it running
You'll be charged for it same thing with Kressel be sure to go to your cresol
Instance and stop it you can't just turn your computer off or close the browser
You actually have to stop an increase or or in paper space and don't forget to do that or you'll end up being charged until
You finally do remember
Okay, so I think that's all the information that you need to get started
Please remember about the forum's okay, if you get stuck at any point check them out
But before you do make sure you read the information on course dot fast at AI for each lesson
Right because that is going to tell you about like things that have changed. Okay, so if there's been some change -
witch
Cupid a notebook provider we suggest using or how to set up paper space
Or anything like that and that'll all be on course doc bastard AI
Okay, thanks very much for watching and look forward to seeing you in the next lesson